It begins like this.
Two billion years ago, an amoeba.
Wait, let's... let's back up.
I've skipped too many connections.
Out of nothing,
in an instant... everything.
An infinite cosmic orgy
of matter and energy,
rubbing, bumping, and grinding together.
There would be no galaxies,
no suns, no planets,
no life without collisions
of heavenly bodies.
Back to our amoeba.
It engulfs a bacterium with unique powers,
and... voilà.
Earth's first
photosynthesis-enabled organism.
Maybe it was chance.
Maybe it was inevitable.
This one changed amoeba
becomes the ancestor
of every living plant on Earth,
which in turn floods the planet with oxygen... paving
the way for every other form of life we know...
leading to more souls, more connections,
and therefore more new worlds
branching outward from the first.
These forces of nature,
when they converge,
be they astronomical collisions,
biological unions,
demonstrate the infinite potential
of our connections.
This truth also extends
to the human heart.
Pack of Stuttons.
No offense,
but how are you gonna pay for these?
I'm gonna use an adBuddy
to cover this purchase.
Those assholes
record client conversations.
AD BUDDY NOT ACCEPTED
National Database of Desires.
The businessmen, ever hear of it?
They know you better than you know you.
- Okay.
- It's not a conspiracy,
just a conspiracy theory.
Hypothesis...
all souls are on a quest to connect.
Corollary...
our minds have no awareness of this quest.
Oh.
Did you know that most quarters have been
swallowed and defecated by a human?
Hypothesis...
all the worlds that almost were
matter just as much as the world we're in.
Corollary...
these hidden worlds cause us great pain.
...no wallet, no shoes.
No idea how I even really got to Poland
in the first place.
Bro, I'm telling you,
this was seriously such a crazy situation.
Th... From Poland... I was in...
I had no idea...
I had no idea how I got there.
Camaraderie, communion,
family, friendship, love, what have you.
We're lost without connection.
EVERYTHING TASTES BETTER
WHEN YOU'RE TOGETHER
...relationships are tough.
Thank you, Friend Proxy.
It's quite terrible...
to be alone.
NOT ALL HUGS ARE CREATED EQUAL
Put simply, my goal is to eradicate all...
unnecessary and inefficient forms
of human pain.
Forever.
We must evolve past our suffering.
It's trash, not a handout. Let's move it.
What are you, a cop?
Not much of a difference authority-wise.
Let's go.
MILGRIM INDUSTRIES
My research into this matter is...
of course, ongoing.
The witness
has already been sworn in.
Mr. Milgrim, can you state for the court
your relationship with the defendant,
Mr. Jed Milgrim?
He's, um...
- He's my brother.
- Thank you.
Have you ever been arrested? - No.
- Are you married?
- No.
- Children?
No.
And can you tell us
about the psychotic break
that you experienced
roughly ten years ago?
- Really?
- I'm just asking.
That's how they're gonna start?
Dad, come on.
It doesn't necessarily mean that
it'll be like that in the trial, Owen,
but, uh, sometimes prosecutors, they...
they try atypical inroads...
to crack you.
That's why we...
we have to prep for the unexpected.
Can you resume, please?
Have you ever been hospitalized
for mental illness?
Yes, ten years ago.
Please explain what happened.
I was hospitalized...
and medicated...
and...
that was the last episode I had.
Wasn't the nature
of this psychosis delusional?
That you sometimes thought you saw
your brother when he wasn't there?
Not exactly.
Just say no.
Then what was the nature
of this psychosis?
Owen, don't you think
that your mental illness
should disqualify you from testifying
as a witness on your brother's behalf?
Look, there's only one question here
that really matters.
Owen, do you know what is real?
One hundred percent.
I'm compos mentis.
Welcome to New York.
And this is Statue of Extra Liberty. Da.
Statue of Extra Liberty. Okay.
How'd the trial prep go
for a naughty brother?
Did you tell them about me?
You're not supposed to be here.
Good.
You're still using the code words,
even though I am technically invisible.
Owen, this week must be
a doozy for you, huh?
You thought you were rid of me,
but I have new information.
This time I know.
You've been chosen to save the world.
You're gonna be a hero.
I don't want this. I don't want it.
I don't want this.
The details of the mission will be
delivered to you by an agent, a woman.
You'll know her
when you see her, trust me.
Just make contact with her.
The pattern is the pattern.
She'll reach you for further instructions!
Don't fuck this up!
Welcome.
Please make a selection to begin.
You selected single ride.
How will you pay?
You selected credit.
Please swipe now.
Declined. Insufficient funds.
Would you like to use an adBuddy
to add funds?
Yes or no?
TIRED OF HERE?
ONE WAY FLIGHTS STARTING AT $1799
Welcome.
AD BUDDY
...train now arriving...
Please step away from the platform edge.
Okay, Mr. Milgrim,
I'm gonna need your attention.
"When tragedy strikes others,
it's sometimes hard to know
what to do until now..."
Owen.
"Daddy's Home. Consider becoming
a temporary volunteer mail-order husband
and changing the lives
of a heartbroken family in your region."
YOU ARE HERE
Okay, well, up next,
we got something called
Neberdine Pharmaceuticals.
"Good afternoon, Owen.
Did you know that your rent comprises
87.2 percent of your annual income?"
Is that actually true?
- I just moved into my own place.
- Manhattan these days...
I'm over in an underground warehouse unit.
Hoboken.
- I actually live in Roosevelt Island.
- Okay, well...
Uh, let's see. Oh-ho-ho.
"A catastrophic interruption
in your professional life,
like a furlough, could ruin you.
Ever thought about supplementing
your income with pharmaceutical testing?"
Friend Proxy.
"Tired of spending your time and energy
making friends?"
And that is why Daddy's Home
is happy to welcome you, Mr. Milgrim.
And I'd have to cover
relocation costs?
And inherit any potential debt
of the deceased.
That doesn't make sense.
So, that's a yes?
To what?
It makes perfect sense.
- We are offering you heroism.
- So this is your office area.
Again, it's a question of commitment.
Your ad is misleading,
'cause you refer to it
as a volunteer opportunity,
but in the end I'd have to pay.
But think about
what you'd be getting.
- A wife, lonely, in need.
- Yeah.
- Owen. It's a done deal.
- I have to go.
Rozo did the anonymous
hammerhead from the top down
and came back
with a 12-bullet short-termer.
- When?
- Well, they randomized the pattern.
We've sent out 30 memos on it
since this morning.
Um, so this furlough,
how long does it last?
- It's temporary.
- Right.
So... when am I back?
Oh, I don't know. I was kidding.
It's probably permanent.
I was using your kind of humor,
when you say something you don't mean
and nobody laughs.
It's... Yeah, it's okay. I'll just...
I'll just dip into my savings.
Bye.
THE PATTERN IS THE PATTERN
Okay, Owen.
- Do you know what I want to do?
- Yes.
Are you sure you know
what I want to do?
Yes.
The way this deprogramming works,
it's not an overnight fix.
You have to listen to it like a mantra.
If you start feeling paranoid,
you play this tape right away, okay?
Okay.
Now, stop me when I say something
that's not true.
The world sends you messages.
Yes.
Words are often code words,
or pass phrases for important secrets.
Yes.
You're visited by a brother
no one else in your family is aware of.
A facsimile of your brother Jed.
- Yes.
- He sends you messages.
Instructions for important missions
you must accomplish.
To see the deeper truth.
He tells you you're meant
to do something big,
something that matters to the world,
and that you're not meant to do it alone.
All you need is a partner.
Yes.
You made a promise to me,
and you made a promise to yourself.
You promised we'd golf together
in Hilton Head.
You sense danger all around you,
but you stay disciplined.
A fight's coming.
Something even bigger than this world.
Possibly extending to multiple galaxies.
- Fourth floor. Thank you.
- Yes.
Hello, Mrs. Finkelstein.
Fuck off, Donovan.
It's, uh... Owen.
- Owen Milgrim...
- Fuck off, Donovan.
Never mind. Good.
Does it feel good to be heard?
Yes.
Does it feel good to know that
you're not alone with this information?
Yeah.
Will you complete your mission?
Maybe.
Am I a trusted messenger?
Yes.
Good.
Then here are your real instructions.
Repeat after me. There is no pattern.
There is no pattern.
I am vulnerable,
but I am not stupid.
I'm vulnerable, but I'm not stupid.
But I will seek out the people
in my life that care about me.
I will seek out the people
in my life who care about me.
I am not the chosen one.
The voices aren't real.
- The voices aren't real.
The voices are just noise.
- The voices are just noise.
I am just a guy
with a vivid imagination.
I'm just a guy
I will most likely
not be the savior of our galaxy.
Hello?
I've got a package
from Neberdine Pharmaceutical Biotech
for an Owen Milgrim.
What?
I've... a package... your name.
Hello?
Hi, Owen.
Did you get what I sent you?
How did you...
I've just been informed
that you qualify as a hero candidate.
- What does that mean?
- It's a term we use
for those who've been specifically
selected for one of our studies.
You're a very desirable individual
to us, Owen.
I've never seen B.N. over-ratios
like this before.
What does a hero candidate do?
Exactly the things
they were born to.
In your case, helping us treat maladies
ranging from sluggishness and depression
to I.B.S, to popcorn problems
and irrational fears.
"Popcorn problems"?
Prostate problems, yes.
Oh, I thought you...
We'll give you all the details
when you come in.
So, we'll see you on Monday?
Good evening, Mr. Milgrim.
Everyone is on the patio for the recital.
Thank you.
Where does she sleep when she stays over?
This one?
Yeah, she's your sister, right?
Or is she a secret agent?
How did you know?
Because I have super-secret sources
at a super-secret agency.
Don't tell anyone.
Okay.
Supper's ready.
Okay, Mom.
I was completely baffled.
You know, I left for school.
Ernie was fine, and then, you know,
the food was in the bowl.
The water was there,
cage was locked up,
and I get back from basketball practice,
- and he's just gone, absolutely...
- The great gerbil escape artist.
- But he wasn't exactly fucking gone.
- Language, Phil.
No, that's correct.
He wasn't exactly fucking gone like that.
- Language, Jed.
- Where'd he go, O?
Maybe you shouldn't curse so much
in front of the children.
- Ah, come on. Tell the rest.
- This is not a farmyard, boys.
So, um, I ask everyone, right?
Everyone's looking around the whole house,
everyone frantic,
and finally Owen, you know,
eventually comes up
and brings me to his room...
How old were you then, Owen?
Like, eight or somethin'?
- Nine.
- Eight or nine, whatever.
And he says... he says,
"Uh, I have to tell you somethin'.
My... my hawk ate Ernie."
"What?" And he points over there,
and there's
this big fuckin' red-tailed hawk
sitting on his desk staring at me.
What eight-year-old has a fuckin' hawk?
Uh, how did you have a hawk?
Um, I rescued it from the park.
I found it with a broken wing
and brought it to my room and fed it.
- Yeah, I forgot.
- You'd feed him.
That was the craziest part. He would
feed it, like a mother bird, you know...
Oh, masticate... No, no, no. Premasticate.
- Yeah, premastication!
- Jed was a chronic masticater.
- How'd you know?
- He'd go blind doing that.
How long did you
take care of the bird for, Owen?
Two or three months,
until it was strong enough
to go into Jed's room
and eat his gerbil, I guess.
But what happened to the hawk?
We set it free.
Oh. Okay.
That reminds me.
Remember when Colby
fell in the Gowanus Canal?
- Remember that day?
- Oh, poor Colby.
- I threw the stick, he didn't go for it...
- So traumatizing.
I told Jed I wouldn't marry him
until they painted you in.
Maybe that's why
we haven't set a date yet.
They're gonna paint me in.
The artist just took
a six-month sabbatical to Nepal,
to study the light.
I lost my job.
I'm sorry, Owen.
It's okay, I'll find a new one.
I'm actually thinking about becoming
a temporary volunteer husband.
You're not serious.
Get rid of my lease,
bounce from widow to widow.
Mm-mm.
Do you ever notice that your plans
always involve starting over...
often with an entirely new identity?
It's a good fantasy.
Pudding's upstairs
by the fireplace, everyone.
Just to get through
the post-dinner conversation.
Think about it.
Seriously...
as a hypothetical.
Say you and I left, right? Tonight.
I got us passports, new identities.
You steal all the money
from Jed's bank account.
We just... do that.
We get a house in the middle of nowhere.
Start again.
Different people.
Are we a married couple?
We don't...
We can be, you know...
We don't have to be. We could be
brother, or sister, or... friends.
So...
tonight, then,
after dessert?
Yeah.
I'm serious. Let's do it.
You're fucking with me.
I got you.
You believed me.
This week's gonna be a living hell for me.
He'll totally win.
He's not guilty.
No chance of a conviction.
It's all just so humiliating.
I mean, it's been going on
for fucking ages,
all just for one day in court.
Because he didn't do it, so...
You're positive?
Right? You were actually with him?
Yes.
- You would make that move.
- What does that even mean?
- "Make that move"?
- That's the move...
Hey, Owen, you're not trying
to sneak off, are you?
No, Dad.
I need a second of your time
before you leave.
Come on, boys, it's time.
- Balderdash!
- Oh!
- Owen, you're staying to play.
- No, I-I have to go.
- I have something...
- You love Balderdash.
No, I don't.
Come on, stay, it will be fun.
I have a fundamental problem
with Balderdash.
I gotta say,
what a delicious meal that was.
- Sure was.
- So good, Mom. So good.
- You used to love Balderdash.
- Oh, no, I didn't.
Who wants ice cream?
- Who wants ice cream? Oh, you do?
- I do!
Of course. But whoever's the quietest
gets ice cream, I promise. Mom.
Oh, are we playing Balderdash, or what?
So, um...
I've been considering...
Considering leaving Roosevelt Island?
- No...
- Oh, thank God.
So, have Hal help you find
something closer.
- Oh, you moving closer?
- I'm not moving closer.
Crazy to think that every word
did get invented.
I-I have to go. Goodbye.
- Wait, you're not playing Balderdash?
- No, I can't. Bye.
Oh, Owen, come on, you love Balderdash.
No, I don't fucking love Balderdash!
Balderdash is bullshit.
- Jesus, Owen.
- Is he off his meds?
I'll walk you to the station.
- Don't worry about Uncle Owen.
- Aggressive.
He's a spaz.
We're gonna get ice cream now.
- Is it a money crisis?
- No.
I know it's an expensive apartment
to rent, but...
Have you... have you thought about a...
a roommate?
No.
I don't know why you won't let us
just buy you a place.
That way you'd have more security.
Or you... you could come and work
for the company.
All your brothers do.
I already agreed, okay?
You don't need to buy me off.
Uh... I don't... I don't follow you.
What...
I will lie for Jed...
next week in court.
I get the expectation.
It's not an expectation, Owen,
it's a gift.
You are giving your brother
the gift of an alibi.
This woman is an opportunist.
She sees an in.
You're protecting him.
You're protecting the family.
I know, I know, it sounds muddled,
but that is the way reality works, Owen.
How's that, Dad?
With... with adjustments.
Just so you know, I got a new job.
Oh? What... what job?
Business... marketing.
It involves travel, so I'll be gone
a couple days next week,
but I'll be back in time for the trial.
And...
don't worry if you can't reach me.
Someone invented a new kind of ham.
Oh.
That's... that's wonderful, Owen.
That's... that's... that's great.
Milgrim men, we always come out on top.
Anyway...
All right.
Hey, Colby, it's a Tristan 500.
- Cleaning in progress.
- No kicking and licking.
SANITATION
NEBERDINE PHARMACEUTICAL BIOTECH
Find the end of your rainbow
at Neberdine Pharmaceutical and Biotech.
Psst, buddy. Which one are you here for?
It should be on the form right there.
It says, uh, U.L.P.
Me too.
That's a good one.
It's the big time.
Get ready to make a lot of fuckin' money.
Carol Cuddy. Carol Cuddy,
please report to D.M. test room three
for A.E.B Phase I.
What do the bombs mean?
High-risk.
That's where the dollars come from.
Apparently, they're havin' some kind
of problem with this new drug.
- I think you should let me do it again.
- Strong stuff. Very trippy shit.
- Who's in charge of the red light?
- That doesn't bother you?
- No.
- I don't fucking understand.
- No risk, no reward.
- I'm supposed to be part of the trial.
- I'm sorry.
- This is fucking bullshit.
John Mallory,
please report to D.M. test room one.
John Mallory, please report to D.M.
test room one for Rumi Phase III.
Patricia. Patricia.
I got bosses around.
- I have to get into that study.
- Ma'am?
You have a daughter. Her name is Usnavy,
and she goes to Hunter College.
Owen Milgrim,
please report to D.M. test room five.
Owen Milgrim, please report to D.M.
test room five for U.L.P. screening.
Steven McDougal,
please report to test room eight.
Steven McDougal, please report
to test room eight for M.S. One Phase II.
Unnecessary.
Try to answer with an emotion,
rather than a description.
Uh... calm.
Justice.
- Is this personalized somehow?
- No.
Focus on your answers.
- Suffocated.
- Good.
Now, Mr. Milgrim...
please turn your attention to me
as I ask you this final question.
Are you gonna ask it?
Does that disqualify me?
Your defense mechanisms are fungible.
You've been accepted.
Find the end of your rainbow
at Neberdine Pharmaceutical and Biotech.
Stop looking at me.
Did... did you...
Did you lose your husband recently?
Huh?
No.
- But I just saw...
- Leave me alone.
Do you play golf in Hilton Head?
I'll kill you.
I have a gun.
Attention, please, all participants
in the U.L.P. Phase III trial,
please look at your lanyards.
If you are an odd number,
please line up at the intake corridor.
All even numbers will be next.
It's Jed.
No, it's Grimsson.
Mustache. No, don't say anything.
Just be cool.
The pattern is the pattern.
The pattern got you here.
Keep trusting the pattern.
She's your handler now.
She has a certain je ne sais quoi.
She's no Olivia, though.
Make contact with her.
Use the code phrase.
If you are an odd number,
please line up at the intake corridor.
The pattern is the pattern.
I know it doesn't make sense.
It doesn't make sense to me either
right now, but it will.
Keep going forward.
Just reach out...
and make contact.
All odd numbers,
line up by the intake corridor.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Sorry.
Robert.
Robert. Robert, wake up.
The odds are here.
Okay.
Let us complete this trial
with none of the old problems, sir.
Yes, Dr. Fujita.
None of the old problems.
As you enter the common room,
you will notice
there are numbers on the pods.
The pod numbers correspond
with the numbers on your lanyards.
Please go to your pod.
That will be your home for the duration
of your stay here with us.
Leaving your pod
at any unauthorized moment
will result in the termination
of your stay here at this trial,
as well as bringing shame
and humiliation upon you.
Once you reach your pod,
an orderly will approach
and begin to inspect your bag.
Once the orderly has inspected your bag,
you will put your bag in your locker.
Once you have done that,
make your way to this gentleman.
He will give you your uniform,
as well as your patented Neberdine shoes,
which you cannot take with you
at the end of the trial.
Once you have your uniforms
and your shoes,
you will make your way back to your pods,
then you will get in your pods
and change clothes in your pods.
There will be no changing in the commons.
Oh, my God!
Condoms are contraband.
- Safety first.
- That's a red flag right there.
Intimacy in this facility is off-limits.
There will be no cohabitation
inside the pods.
Once the curfew starts, lights go out.
You're not supposed to be here.
Please.
What are my instructions?
The pattern is the pattern.
You're my contact.
What are my instructions?
Please turn off the pattern.
Please turn off...
- Owen.
- ..tight schedule.
We will tell you when there is mealtime.
Your instructions are to go back
to your pod and await my signal.
...two Etch A Sketches and one
Lite-Brite. Please don't fight over them.
I'm going to save the world.
We will tell you
when there's recreation time.
- Yes.
- We will also tell you when...
- You're gonna save the world.
- And we will tell you when to sleep.
- But not if you blow our cover.
- ...expecting. Thank you.
Is that working for you?
Okay, I understand.
If you're having trouble
getting into your pod,
there is also a little ladder underneath
that will help you get into your pod.
Also note, from here on in,
you will be referred to
as the number on your lanyard.
You are the Odds.
Attention.
Please give your attention
to Dr. Muramoto and Dr. Fujita.
They will be supervising your trials.
Welcome, subjects.
You made the right choice.
It's time to start your lives again.
You don't fuck this up...
I won't fuck this up.
Just kidding.
You're the last one.
And then it is fuck you... forever.
A
You have not lost.
There is a way.
A way for you to hold in your hand
the power of the galaxy.
What do you mean?
We thought to use...
all of this to conquer only Neptune.
But why?
Why merely Neptune?
That gives you the power
to control every planet in the galaxy.
Yes.
Every planet in the galaxy.
I can penetrate into
the most secret chambers of the galaxy.
Fuck you.
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS DOG?
"GROUCHO" VERY GENEROUS REWARD!
''Silken smooth,
and shiny, and soft,
these curls won't abandon you.
Creamazone means lasting hold
and definition.''
You ready for another one?
Do I have a choice?
Oh, your options with AdBuddies
are limitless.
Okay? That's what makes us
superior to PallyAds.
I was joking.
- "Not enough time...
- Wait, when you say "limitless"...
do you mean actually limitless?
Like, if I needed a bus ticket to Salt Lake
City and I brought you with me to pay for it?
I mean, not necessarily you, specifically,
but one of you...
to pay for the hotel and meals,
and the bus ticket back,
would that be possible?
No one's ever asked me that.
Well, it would require you
to view thousands of ads, but...
Yes, I suppose it could be possible.
If that was, um...
What?
Sounds like it might be kind of fun.
Yeah.
What's in Salt Lake City?
Um, my little sister.
I owe her a visit.
I'm gonna read you this time...
because I am healthy Annie now,
and healthy people read books...
and travel, and exercise...
and take care of their minds.
DON QUIXOTE
- Where's Jackie?
- She's in the shitter.
What the fuck? Did you take my money?
Yeah, I took your money.
You haven't paid rent in three months.
I haven't had a job in five months.
Well, maybe you should be
a little more goal-oriented.
Can I at least have 20 bucks?
Yes.
Cleaning is progress.
Error. Error.
SANITATION
Can't be processed.
Error.
Error. Error.
Can't be processed.
Error.
Can't be processed. Error.
Can't be processed. Can't be processed.
Error.
Godspeed, little shit-eater.
Hello?
Are you dead?
No.
Good.
You gonna come out today?
Your yard is a fucking mess.
"All things excellent
are as difficult as they are rare."
Mmm. Is that Rilke?
Spinoza.
I like it.
I just came by to tell you
I'm gonna go away for a while.
I was thinking about taking the bus
to Salt Lake, go see Ellie.
You could come.
We could go together.
Oh, I'm really busy right now.
Is the combination to the safe
still the same?
I just need to borrow a little bit
for my bus ticket.
I changed it.
To what?
Your birthday.
Got tired of thinking of your mother
every time.
Promise me you're gonna eat
while I'm gone?
I got you cereal.
Apple Jacks?
Of course.
Hey, maybe when I'm back
we could go to Totonno's for dinner.
Maybe.
Okay. Love you, Dad.
TIRED OF HERE?
BROOKLYN PUBLIC LIBRARY BUS TERMINAL
12:25 - 706 - SALT LAKE, GATE 14
BUS INFORMATION
A
Fuck you.
I need more.
I can't.
But why, though?
That's a great move, dude-wad.
You dirty motherfucker.
Come on, bud.
Calvin.
It was a one-time thing.
My dad had a mini-stroke
after I stole 'em.
Why do you even like that ULP shit?
- It's dark.
- So, what if I really,
really need some more,
however I can get it?
I don't got all day here, pal.
Sign up for a Neberdine study.
Help make my dad's company millions.
That's it, I just sign up?
- That was pathetic.
- No.
- They screen you.
- Checkmate.
You could be testing deodorant for a week.
I'm fucked.
- Just lost a hundred dollars.
- What's yours is mine now, bitch.
Hey. Hey, you're my friend.
Yeah?
- And can I say something, as your friend?
- Sure, yeah.
You sound like a junkie.
I'm not a junkie.
I'm a recreational drug user.
Like you, by the way.
- What is the name of the person at intake?
- I can't tell you that.
ULP's gotten way more secretive
since the suicides.
Give me a name.
Gesundheit. Gesundheit!!
Rude.
Lugo.
Patricia Lugo.
Thank you.
Nice friend.
It's yours.
Right into the eucalyptus fund.
Three hundred to get started.
- To blackmail somebody?
- Yeah.
Okey-dokey.
Who's your target?
I can't read your handwriting.
Patricia Lugo.
She's the intake director
at Neberdine Pharmaceuticals and Biotech.
You going in and getting high
and robbing the place?
Patricia Lugo,
Nerberdine Pharmaceuticals Biotech.
She paid Zip Dox to have
her public arrest records scrubbed.
Zip Dox is Shit Dox. Easy to unscrub.
This is legal, right?
Think we'd have it on the storefront
if the Banner Act didn't make it legal?
Yes.
You gotta pay us more
than she paid Shit Dox.
Five hundred.
You get a free calendar.
Patricia Lugo. Gambling addict,
disorderly arrest in Atlantic City.
Lost custody of her daughter, Usnavy.
Goes to Hunter.
Good job, had it for 18 months.
Probably had records scrubbed
so she could get it.
You want
the whole skeleton-closet file?
I could threaten
to kidnap the daughter too.
No.
- That shit always works.
- No, it's fine. I don't...
- I don't want to harm her in any way.
- Uh-huh.
Okay.
Here's your calendar. Other options.
Volunteers at CP Center,
user of Friend Proxy,
pays way too much for luggage...
Wait, Friend Proxy?
Does she have appointments coming up?
Ah...
Interception.
Hm?
Patricia?
Juanita.
Oh!
Hey.
- It's so good to see you again.
- You too. You too.
You know, um,
every time I walk in this place,
I get pulled back into this room,
you know?
Oh, me too.
Me too.
I just love little trees.
I meant because of how we met.
- Right here.
- Sure.
- At the bonsais.
- Oh, yeah. That too. That too.
Do you remember that summer?
How much fun we had, right?
Oh!
Running up and down Coney every day...
Eating icy pops.
Yeah, when we took the train,
with Uncle Liam.
Now, who the fuck is... Uncle Liam?
I'm sorry. I-I don't...
Do you want to start over or something?
Seriously? What, then, you new?
No. I'm...
What...? What's your rating?
'Cause you really don't have
a very good feel for people, honey.
You're using a service
that gives you pretend friends.
I have real friends.
This is just more convenient.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you have friends?
You know what?
I don't even work for Friend Proxy.
All right?
I canceled your appointment,
and I am here to fuck up your life, lady.
I'm gonna blackmail the shit out of you.
What?
What? What are you
talking about? Who are you?
Forget it. I'm sorry.
- No, no, no, no, wait. Who are you?
- No, I'm really sorry, okay? I'm sorry.
Hey.
Can I sit with you?
I'm just trying to understand.
I'm a bit confused.
Am I a mark?
Yeah.
For what? I'm...
I'm broke.
I was trying to get into a study
at your work.
And I said I'm sorry,
so can you leave now, please?
Why?
- I really don't need...
- No, really, I'm asking you...
why?
Is this some AA shit?
I'm enjoying this pond.
You remind me of my little girl,
that's all.
If there's anything I can help...
So...
why?
Because I am addicted to a drug
that your company's testing.
That's not the "why" I'm asking.
What "why" are you asking?
Five years ago, my sister and I got into
a really bad fight.
Very, very bad.
And I can't fix it.
So there's this rock
that sits in my stomach, this cold rock.
Like a boulder, and it's just there...
all the time.
And I found this pill...
It helps me get through the day.
It's not hurting anyone.
And it makes me feel good. It is
the only thing that makes me feel good.
Have you tried talking to her?
I can't.
Why shouldn't I be able to take
a pill like that whenever I want?
You should, hon.
If it ain't hurting anyone.
Hmm?
Super happy.
Helpful.
Togetherness.
You don't have to rush.
Okay.
Sorry.
Sisters.
Making faces at each other.
It's supposed to be an emotion.
What you feel.
Fine.
Now, please turn your attention to me...
as I ask you this final question.
The test is complete.
Please go back
to the reception area and wait.
Did I...?
Did I pass the test?
What was that last question?
I was telling the truth
about all those pictures.
- This test is not about the truth.
- Well, what is it about?
Defense mechanisms.
I don't have fucking defense mechanisms.
I think you should let me do it again.
Who's in charge of the red light?
I... I don't fucking understand because
I am supposed to be part of the trial.
I'm sorry.
This is fucking bullshit.
Patricia. Patricia.
No. No, no, no, no, no. No more favors.
I got bosses around. No more. Go.
- We had a deal.
- I said I could funnel you through ULP.
You failed the intake test.
It is out of my hands.
No, I have to get into that study,
Patricia.
All the way. I can't.
Move on, please.
There you go. Thank you.
Patricia, may I speak with you, please?
You have a daughter.
Her name is Usnavy,
and she goes to Hunter College.
And if you don't get me into that study,
you're never gonna see her again.
What?
Yeah, I know a guy who has a van,
and if anything happens to me,
he knows what to do.
You're fucking crazy.
I'm not fucking crazy, Patricia.
I'm just goal-oriented.
Two minutes.
Go sit over there.
Owen Milgrim,
please report to DM Test Room five.
Owen Milgrim, please report
to DM Test Room five for ULP screening.
What's the color?
This one's the same, that's...
Well, I guess it's kind of gray.
- Hi. Excuse me.
- Hi.
I have some good news.
We're going to upgrade you.
Oh.
Just between you and me,
it's a much, much safer trial.
Okay. Um, does it have the same pay?
- You just hand this over to me.
- Okay.
And you can go and talk
to my colleague over there at the desk,
and sort it all out.
Okay.
So... so, what do you mean, "safer trial"?
It's fine.
Your daughter is safe.
For now.
The human brain is vast as the cosmos,
and equally unexplored. We here at
Neberdine Pharmaceutical Biotech
are pioneering a revolutionary procedure
that will unlock
the secret mysteries of the mind,
and replace old-fashioned talk therapy...
forever.
Sorry, Sigmund.
Hello. I'm Dr. James K. Mantleray.
And I'm Dr. Robert Muramoto.
Welcome to Phase III of the ULP testing.
You are not only participants
in a pharmaceutical drug trial,
you are pioneers
at the forefront of a new world.
You may notice you're here
with 11 other subjects.
But don't worry, your experiences here,
likely very powerful,
will be private and discreet,
and entirely your own.
No one sees into your heads...
And the multiple fantasy cells
hiding inside there.
...but us.
Now you're probably wondering,
"How does it work?"
And it's simple.
Three pills taken in three steps...
A B C
...analyzed by the most sophisticated
mega-computer ever developed:
the GRTA.
Hello, friends.
I'm a smart computer.
After ingesting the pills,
the GRTA's cutting-edge
artificial intelligence
will identify, map, and confront
the learned programming of your brain.
At the end of this trial,
don't be surprised if you experience
pure, unaffected joy.
You'll be born again,
but not as a baby.
Now, let's take a closer look.
Pill A: The diagnostic stage.
Pill A seeks out your core traumas
and pulls them to the surface.
We call it Agonia.
Through your memories,
we'll see the worst moments of your life.
But don't worry... it's safe.
We observe, using powerful
microwave technology,
the known and unknown anchors of pain
in your personal history
in order to create an arborization map
that the GRTA will use as a guide
for pills B and C.
Pill B: Behavioral.
- Time to show your...
- Blind spots!
Unfortunately, the brain
is remarkably skilled
at protecting itself.
With the second pill, you can identify
self-defense mechanisms, blind spots,
and the mazes and walls
that your mind creates to hide yourself...
from you.
Finally, it's time for...
confrontation.
Pill C: Confrexia.
This is what has eluded psychoanalysts
since the discovery of the unconscious.
The end...
of the rainbow.
Confrontation and acceptance.
Once we've identified your core traumas
and mapped
your bio-psycho-social symptoms,
the GRTA mega-computer remaps
a more efficient system,
custom-tailored to you,
forging healthier pathways with powerful,
non-surgical microwave technologies.
Welcome to the start of your new life.
You will never be the same again.
Any questions?
Good.
Even subjects, we'll provide you
with your pre-weighed meal,
as the odd-numbered subjects...
begin the trial.
Odd-numbered subjects,
I assume you know who you are by now,
please stand up, form a line,
and get ready to begin your trials.
As for the rest of you, please just
sit tight. We'll get to you soon.
Line up in order, please.
Number one in the front.
Everybody thought I was crazy,
but they were all wrong.
- All right.
- We'll talk about this later.
Number nine.
"I dried my tears and armed my fears
With ten thousand shields and spears.
Soon my Angel came again;
I was armed, he came in vain;
For the time of youth was fled,
And grey hairs were on my head."
Oh, Robert, how poetic.
I'm glad you like it.
Oh, I loved it.
Now back I go, into their minds.
One, three, five, seven, nine, eleven.
When you reach your seats,
you can put on your aprons.
- What's the vest for?
- Check number one's headrest.
It's like being at a dentist's office.
- What's the vest for?
- Precautionary.
Did they say anything about radiation?
Precautionary.
The vest protects your important parts
from the nominal amount
of residual headset radiation.
Can you check number one, please?
Final stages checks, please. - Cooling.
- Operational.
Electrical.
Stable.
Med profile.
- Uploaded and carved out.
- Take one of each.
I can see Gertie's safety net
is supple and responsive.
She liked what you read.
I know.
Take one of each.
Take one of each, please.
Wait!
Dr. Fujita will tell you
when you can take it.
A
The data we collect from our subjects,
in the next three days,
is absolutely vital
to the success of this trial.
What's more, their lives are in our hands.
No more mistakes.
Subjects, please ingest your pill
with your water.
GRTA
Visual check clear. Go to blue?
Going to blue.
Let's lay them down gently, people.
Hard entry is our enemy.
Tank is full.
Please remove nozzle.
Have a nice day.
Think fast.
Oh.
There's 24,000 words in there.
What?
You know... picture?
Oh.
Twenty-four thousand... words.
Cute.
How many words is that?
One.
- Okay, '80s.
- There's a supernatural element.
Yep, but it has to make you cry.
- Oh, it's this one.
- Oh-oh. It's a body-switch movie.
He's him, and he's him.
And they crashed their dirt bikes
into each other,
they woke up in the hospital,
and they've switched bodies.
And the young one
has been masturbating constantly.
Now they're on this hijinks-filled
wackadoo road trip that ends with...
a secret sect of Utah businessmen...
that, um...
mmm...
practice soul-swapping.
I'm surprised you didn't add sodomy.
That's pretty light for you.
Well, I'm not finished yet.
It's tragic, because that old man
is now in this young body,
and he's gonna leave his grandson,
just ditch him,
and let him slip off into Alzheimer's.
There she is.
I'm actually pissed about this.
Hey!
I see you, motherfucker!
That wasn't your body in the first place!
You got to give it back!
You can't cheat Father Time!
Apparently in Colorado,
fast lane means slow lane.
Oh, my God! That's a bumpy road!
To the left.
To your left.
Okay.
Right now, it looks like you're sort of,
like, fondling the underside of it.
- I am not. What am I supposed to do?
- Just, like, give it some gumption.
- That's perfect. Like that?
- Yes!
Stay there. Stay.
One.
Two.
Three.
That's really funny.
Can I have the camera back, please?
No.
It's pretty.
I wanted to take a nice picture.
Well, I am the designated documentarian,
so no.
Yeah, I know. I gotta go.
- Love you.
- Love you too.
See you soon, honey.
- Bye.
I like this.
What?
Just... doing something with you.
I don't know, it's...
- It's been a while.
- Was that Mom...
that you were talking to just now?
No, that was Ben.
I just told him that we'd be there
by tomorrow night.
I just figured because you and Mom
have reconnected... or whatever.
I didn't reconnect with her, okay?
She wrote me a letter,
said it was an emergency,
that she needed something,
- so I called her back, once.
- Oh, my God.
- Here, take it. Read it.
- No. God.
- I'm not mad.
- I didn't say you were.
- Stop.
- I didn't say you were mad.
Let's watch a movie.
Nothing to think over.
Okay.
They're trying to say that I'm in a gang.
- They think that I'm the leader of a gang.
- Well, you told them.
You waste his time and mine.
- Oh, no, thank you.
- No, can we...?
Stop, I like this movie. I like it.
Leave it.
He requires more serious...
Annie's favorite.
I can't believe
you like this fantasy shit.
But it's real.
Annie, I'm Ellia,
your cursed Elven sister.
Rescue me.
From what?
From a normal life.
That is all on you.
Okay.
I've got a fantasy for you.
About a girl
moving her life to Salt Lake City,
because that's
where her fiancé has been transferred...
because she thinks it'd make her happy.
But she... But she's afraid...
of a nice family that stays together...
a nice job,
nice kids.
Afraid because maybe
she can't maintain that...
stability.
Maybe she'll just realize that isn't
what she wanted, and she'll just...
fuck it all up and...
her kids along with it.
But she doesn't.
It works.
It works out fine.
Sounds like a fantasy
of someone who gave up.
You have such a thing.
- A thing?
- Mm-hmm.
With, like, going eight levels too harsh.
- No, don't do that.
- Do what?
Don't guess what you think I think
and then say it like it's coming from you.
You don't think
that I have my own doubts, Annie?
You're so caught up
with your own narcissism.
- I'm sorry, my narcissism?
- The fact you can't take care of anything,
- or keep one relationship going.
- I'm sorry about your dog.
Your fucking Mom-like narcissism.
- I loved him too!
- Even the whole armpit pictures.
What point are you trying to make?
That I'm fucking stupid
for wanting to remember a nice trip?
Because I'm sad.
I'm sad that I'm moving away from you!
It's hard to talk to you
when you're this emotional.
You're the one acting like Mom.
You know, I have my things too, I just...
I just don't broadcast them to the world.
Is that what I do?
You also fucking lie constantly.
Every second, of every day,
of your entire fucking life
is broadcasting how normal you are.
You're so desperate for someone
to tell you you're okay.
I don't know how this started.
I'm sorry.
I was just trying to talk to you.
You don't have to shut down
just because I'm saying something real.
I'm not shutting down.
Can I say one last real thing?
Every time I think of New York,
without you in it...
This is seriously true, this isn't a lie.
...I feel happy.
Because now I won't have to feel bad
about not calling you,
or doing anything with you.
You'll be far away.
And we can grow apart...
and we won't have to pretend we didn't.
I'm gonna miss you too, Annie.
Do you want to take an actual picture?
Of both of us?
- I'm not stupid.
- What?
It's the perfect time
to fuck with me again.
No, I'm not fucking with you.
I'm not. I'm being serious.
Okay.
I do want to remember this.
My... The camera is in my bag.
Here, I'll take it.
- Hold the wheel.
- Okay.
They should have, like, a stick
for something like this.
Three.
Two.
- One.
- That's so annoying.
That was fucking funny.
No, it's not funny anymore.
- Give it to me.
- Come on.
- Annie... No, I bought it.
- Ellie, stop. Come on.
- I did take a picture of my armpit.
- Why won't you take the picture?
Welcome back, subjects.
Welcome back.
Ten seconds until reentry, people.
Here they come.
Welcome back, subjects.
Welcome back.
Huh?
What was that?
It was fucking unethical.
You waived ethics in your consent form.
Talk to me. Are we liking what
we're seeing on the neuromatrices?
Clean narrative data
from all but Subject One.
I'm not positive
he was actually down.
- What about Nine?
- I don't know what to tell you.
Brain structure tells me
she's been there many times before.
She's already got the grooves
of this narrative.
That was, uh... overwhelming.
- Wait till you take the second one.
- Friendly reminder,
please do not discuss your experience
with any other subjects.
Post-phase evaluations
will occur in ascending order,
so please settle in
and wait comfortably in the commons
until your number is called.
Mr. One, please report
to the post-exam test room.
Thank you.
Please describe
your emotional state
upon waking from the pill.
Um... Fragile.
Maybe sad.
Mm-hmm.
Also hungry. You need snack?
Bleeding.
Emotional state.
Emotions.
Bleeding.
Internally.
You look tired.
I'm exhausted.
And devastated.
But satisfied.
I want to know more about the second pill.
Why?
I just do.
Um...
S... I'm speechless.
Anything else?
I'm speechless.
I'll trust you too.
I won't count it.
For me, it was a hurricane.
Horrible.
1999.
It took my Herbert.
You like the complicated ones, I see.
- I'm so sorry to hear that.
- It wasn't the best of marriages.
- I don't even know her.
- Are any of them?
- Nothing to be ashamed of.
- Don't say that.
These places all end up like camp.
Everyone falls in love in two hours.
It can get silly.
- You haven't remarried?
- I would never.
I was on a Phase I
of a GI treatment in Houston,
one of the rats proposed
on the second day.
Of course, by that time
we all had the radioactive shits.
You know what was odd though?
What the pill made me see
was not like I remember it.
Was that a memory,
or was it... something else?
One, Five, Nine.
Dr. Muramoto wants to see you
in his office.
- We've been red-flagged.
- What does that mean?
I do 20, 30 of these a year
all over the country.
It's good money
if you can work the system.
When they call you in right away,
that means they caught something.
What do they usually do?
Enhanced interrogation?
No.
They red flag you, they mark your file,
they ask you a bunch of questions.
They're gonna document the case
so they don't have to pay.
- Then they kick you out.
- I didn't do anything wrong.
Every time,
it doesn't matter what you say.
Mr. Five, come in.
We're fucked.
I didn't take the pill
in case you needed to activate me.
Owen...
I'm sorry...
about what I said earlier. I...
sort of...
I kind of lied to get into the study,
and it seemed like you might be a problem,
so I just said what you needed to hear.
But you knew my name.
I saw you in the ads.
You said there was a larger pattern.
Well, I knew your name because
they said it on the intercom at reception.
And the ads, I sold my face
to a stock service four years ago,
so it's...
And...
as far as I can tell, there is no plan
or pattern to the universe.
It's just chaos.
I'm sorry.
Why are you here?
Your turn.
Yo, can I get my condoms back?
You don't get those condoms back.
Really sorry for the confusion.
There are inconsistencies
with your participation in this study.
Oh, okay.
And I'm gonna need you
to recount what happened in your mind
after taking the pill,
and verify your experience
of your core trauma.
It's supposed to be
the worst day of your life, right?
Is that what you experienced?
It was intense.
Describe intense... with details.
Well, when I took the "A" pill...
the light changed...
and I was standing
in my parents' house.
Gimlet?
Oh, what's that?
It's a gimlet.
Thanks.
It was seven months ago,
my brother's engagement party,
and I had just switched
to a new medication.
You like her, don't you?
Yeah, Adelaide's great.
I mean, you really like her.
What do you want, Jed?
Listen, I... I wanted to...
I wanted to ask you directly,
you know, because sometimes...
You're gonna help me out, right?
So long as you didn't do it.
I did... I didn't do it. God...
Nice to meet you.
It really doesn't matter
what happened, right?
You of all people would understand that.
Of course it matters.
It's the only thing that matters.
- Oh, what's real matters?
- Yes.
Okay. Hilarious. Hilarious, but okay.
Can I ask you something?
Can you imagine what Mom and Dad would do
if they found out
you had another incident?
Maybe write threatening letters
to very powerful people.
The mayor, the head of the FBI,
Secret Service.
Tell them how you see a pattern
in the universe,
and how you have to take 'em down
before it's too late.
Maybe sprinkle a little anthrax in there.
You can't do that.
I'm joking.
I'm joking. Jesus, lighten up.
Who said I'd do that, right?
But seriously...
someone could do that to you, right?
With your history,
you'll end up in the fuckin' loony bin.
It's like someone making up
whatever they want about me,
and I end up humiliated.
And it didn't even happen.
We're in the same boat.
You see that, right?
Anyway, I love you.
Yeah.
I wouldn't want that to happen
to anyone in our family.
I gotta go make a speech.
Yikes!
Wish me luck.
Dad.
Oh, there he is.
Um, listen.
Hey, everyone, thank you for...
Where are you hid...?
Don't hide. Come here.
Thank you everyone for coming.
Um, I would like to make a toast
to Adelaide, my Hempstead hamster.
- That's in the bedroom, right?
- Okay, stop.
But, um, I don't know if you guys heard,
she's engaged to be my... my bride.
I don't deserve her, that's for sure.
She doesn't deserve this,
but I'm gonna do it anyway.
- What are you gonna do?
- Dad, you're the man. Start it up.
Owen.
Owen!
So Sting was at this party?
No, he was singing Sting.
Did you make up that story?
No, I did not.
According to our readings,
you were conscious, Mr. One.
You did not take the pill.
No, that's... that's not possible.
Now, you are going to take that.
- I already took it.
- Don't lie.
If you don't take it,
I'll have security escort you
from this facility,
with no money,
no honor,
just shame.
No.
- Take it now.
- No.
I said take it.
No.
Drink.
Swallow!
Why were you in there so long?
What'd he say?
Could you tell Miss Nine
to come in, Mr. One?
He wants you to go in there.
I don't know how
you had access to the pill,
but analysis of the biodata indicates
that you have been using it compulsively.
I haven't.
I sympathize with you.
The "A" experience, on its own,
can be a seductive demon.
What are you talking about?
Most people wouldn't understand
why someone wants to revisit a trauma
again and again,
even take pleasure from it.
Most people, wouldn't.
But you do.
People like that
don't want to move forward.
I don't deserve to.
Don't you?
I want to move forward.
I want to know what the second pill does.
People who feel they deserve loss...
might try to move forward.
They might taste recovery...
but they always end up going back.
Why?
Be...
Dr. Muramoto?
Is...
Is this...
part of...?
Is this a test?
Or is that the test?
You wanna see if I'll answer it?
I can wait.
I'll wait forever.
Are you actually dead?
Fuck!
Owen, I need your help.
- What?
- Just get the fuck in here!
Do not let anyone come in this door.
- Did you kill him?
- No, I didn't fuckin' kill him.
He just died.
Sometimes people just die.
He made me take a pill.
What'd you see?
Olivia.
- We were studying.
- Is that your girlfriend?
No.
It's a girl I liked.
She asked me to help her
with her, uh, history finals.
I, like, wanted to talk to her
all semester.
And I was on my way to the library,
and I saw him.
Grimsson.
That was the first time
he ever came to me.
And he told me to watch out for Olivia,
and I just realized she was a plant.
My parents had paid her
to pretend to like me.
They were listening in.
My brothers were listening in.
They were just laughing at me.
My mind kept racing.
Like, someone had given her
information on me.
How she was getting paid
for every minute she made me happy...
and that my parents
paid her to marry me...
and grow old with me...
and have a family and seven kids.
I started asking her
if her name was even... Olivia.
And... she's like, "Are you okay?"
I said, "No, I'm not okay.
None of this is real.
None of this is real."
Sounds like you were having a day.
What?
That's what my mom used to call it
when she got her wires crossed.
Doctors called it a BLIP.
Brief and limited psychosis.
I didn't know that.
I...
I just started screaming at her.
I just yelled
some fucked up things at her.
And other people started looking at me,
and I started throwing books at them
and screaming at them.
And I knew I was right.
I was so sure I was right.
Have you ever just felt unbelievably sure
that you were right
and everyone else was wrong?
All the time.
I'll do yours.
Where did you end up?
Strapped to a gurney
in a little room by myself...
screaming for my mom.
That's rough.
Let's go back out there and pretend
nothing fucked up happened.
The food cubes being distributed
during Meal Time
deliver a specific amount
of nutrients and calories to the body.
That means that your plates
at the end of Meal Time
need to be happy plates.
Does everyone know what a happy plate is?
A happy plate is a clean plate.
I can't eat.
You have to.
It's not to make me happy,
but to make science happy.
Tastes like the inside
of my cat's uterus.
Stay out of your cat's uterus.
Is this food?
Tell me why the pill
was so important to you
that you lied to get in here
and you tricked me.
I never would have messed with you
if I knew all that stuff had happened.
The BLIP.
It's okay. It's not your fault.
My sister and I were in a car crash
five years ago.
The driver passed out
behind the wheel of a semi-truck.
He had been driving for 30 hours.
He was high on NoDoze.
His name was Greg F.U.N. Nazlund.
His middle name was "fun."
It was his fucking fault
if we're talking about fault.
Every time I take that pill,
I have to live through
the worst day of my life,
just like you did.
I have to hear myself say the worst...
ugliest things I've ever said to anyone.
And it ends with the worst thing
that ever happened.
I fucking love it.
Why?
Because I get to be with her.
Oh, they found him.
I thought he was napping
when I first came in.
Poor Robert.
It's a catastrophe.
Want me to bring in a team,
get him out of here?
No. Leave him.
I have to go up to the 77th floor.
It was a past life.
An old life.
Lies forced us apart...
and now we can't remember.
No... I remember.
We were lovers.
Now we're gonna be together forever.
High Priestess of Atlantis...
can you feel that?
My energy in your chest?
I can feel it.
Good.
- Now, put your hands on me.
- Okay.
That's excellent.
- See what she does with a ping-pong.
- She shot them...
It was cute, but I wasn't into it,
y'know?
- Why weren't you into it?
- It was weird.
Fabulous.
That's good. That's good.
That's good.
Oh, that's... excellent.
James.
- Oh, my God.
- That's excellent.
- Oh, that's excellent.
- James!
I'm sorry to...
to walk in on you like this, but...
I still have my key.
I thought we had agreed...
that you wouldn't bother me
while I was working.
I need your help.
The very fact that you braved
the outside world for me
tells me this is an emergency.
Let me guess. You're having trouble
dampening the reality test
when it drops to NREM 3.
Now Dr. Muramoto has begged you
to come and beg me
- to come help him.
- He's dead.
He was freebasing an A/C mixture.
Uh-huh.
And who's going to replace him?
You.
- Don't fuck with me, Azumi.
- I'm not, James.
We need your help to finish.
Of course I'll need several minutes
to get my affairs in order, but...
yes.
I'll be right outside.
When is this fucking horse gonna die?
I don't have my security card.
Thank you for braving
the outside world for me.
Thank you for inventing this treatment.
Does Gertie know I'm here?
I haven't had a chance to tell her yet.
Hello.
It's...
excellent to see you again.
James.
What a nice surprise!
Are you gonna show your face?
All right.
Oh...
By the way, I thought you should hear it
from me first that Dr. Muramoto is dead.
Oh!
And I'm once again at the helm of this...
project.
I see.
Thank you for telling me.
Did Muramoto have access
to a beta headset?
Yes.
Sometimes he used it
when they were red flags. Why?
I'll address the subjects tomorrow myself.
They can't be spooked by a death.
And sometimes the arrival
of a new authority figure
could be equally upsetting.
Either is a data taint.
Last thing we want is a data taint.
Yeah.
We need all the data we can get.
Number Five...
he just brought rubbers, so...
he can stay, right?
Azumi.
Yes.
When an addict dies,
do you think it's suicide?
I believe Robert was optimistic.
I think he just made a mistake.
I'm sorry about Robert.
How are you feeling?
I feel...
I have all the feels.
Behavioral tomorrow.
What do you think
they'll all see in themselves?
I don't know. Get some rest.
Good night, Azumi.
Good night, James.
- What's wrong with fish sauce?
- There's nothing wrong with fish sauce.
Good morning.
Could I have everyone's attention
for a moment?
My name...
is Dr. James K. Mantleray.
Unfortunately, Dr. Muramoto
has had a family emergency,
so I will personally be assuming
oversight duties
of this iteration of the ULP.
Uh, I believe in this treatment.
And I believe in the idea
that we can all be...
uh...
fixed.
Pain...
uh, can be destroyed.
But it can't without trials
like this, so...
I guess I want to thank you all
for being the brave explorers...
that you are.
Uh, great adventurers on the precipice of
mankind's last, great, hidden frontier:
Mindlantis.
I'm seeing soothing
from the white.
Good. They're settling in.
And there's no reason
for any of them to be nervous.
Exposure elements stacked and loaded?
Affirmative.
Safety Net confirm.
Gertie is present and caring.
Okay, people,
let's illuminate some blind spots.
Azumi.
I'd like to administer
the behavioral pill.
It's been a while.
Be my guest, Dr. Mantleray.
Subjects, please ingest the pill.
All clear.
Going to green.
...comes down to the butter.
- Everyone will tell you to bake...
- Bruce?
...with unsalted butter,
- but I tend to disagree...
- Brucie?
...because using salted butter
in the mix...
Bruce?
You fell asleep in front of the TV again.
You got to get up.
Okay, and...
Well, I know we're all worried
about our cholesterol these days,
but if you truly are...
Hey.
Is there any coffee?
Yeah, I just made some.
Big day today.
You say that every morning.
Well, today I mean it.
Toss? Keep?
Keep.
I'm saving it.
SEE HER SEE YOU SEE WE
DR. GRETA MANTLERAY
HOST OF 150 MINUTES WITH GRETA
All right, Dr. Greta,
let's fix this marriage.
Hmm.
SHE'S OFTEN TELLING YOU WHAT SHE NEEDS.
YOUR JOB AS HER HUSBAND IS TO HEAR IT.
DEPARTMENT OF MOTOR VEHICLES
NOW SERVING
Oh, that's me.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. That's me.
Oh, uh, that's okay.
I'm gonna wait for her. You go ahead.
How can I help you, dear?
I am here to report a dangerous driver.
This is form DS-7, including my anecdote.
My kids play on that street.
You don't have the name and address
of the driver.
Well, if I had his name and his address,
I'd go over to his house
and I'd have dealt with him myself.
You really shouldn't do that.
This is his license plate number.
Can you get any stuff from that?
Well, I'm not allowed
to give you that information, hon,
but I could file a report.
I don't know if you really wanna
bother with this,
because they take such a long time.
Yeah, I'm seeing his address now,
so I can submit this thing.
You know what?
Now that I'm here actually doin' it,
I feel like a snitch.
And I ain't one.
But thanks. You've been helpful.
How'd it go?
Failed the written again.
I'm sorry, babe.
Next time.
Hey, wanna get a doughnut
at Lucky's or somethin'?
No, I wanna go to 534 Ashton Place.
You don't need a map.
You married Magellan.
Uh-huh.
Hey...
what baby wants, baby gets.
Fudgin' seat belt.
- You okay? - Yeah, it's stiff. You know.
- Go all the way back... - Yeah.
- ...and pull it.
- No, I know.
534 Ashton Place.
On a need-to-know basis.
Eight minutes, tops.
Oh, in your dreams, Bruce.
I'm gonna put it on sport mode,
Mario Andretti...
- Oh!
- There we are. There we are.
All right, eight minutes.
We did it.
- Perfect!
- Okay.
I'm just a guy
- who knows his way around.
- Ooh, Brucie, pull there.
- Here?
- Park there.
Okay.
Here we go.
Them sons of bitches.
Wait.
When we go in there,
you're gonna distract them.
What? Distract who?
The guys in the store, Bruce.
It's August, it's 98 degrees.
Why are we going to a fur store?
Just... Go on. Here, go ahead. Go.
It's a different guy.
It's not them.
He's a salesperson.
Welcome to Furs by Sebastian.
I'm him.
How can I help you today?
Uh...
I'm... I'm looking for something to wear...
uh, to the opera.
Is your bathroom in the back?
Oh, right here, hon.
- Okay, I'm just gonna...
- Uh...
- Where... Where are... uh...
- You're just in time.
Our summer sale is just ending.
Take a look over here.
See what speaks to you.
I think you'd look
really stunning in a mink.
You don't choose a fur. It chooses you.
Take a look.
Hold on, Lance. I'm sendin' a fax.
PRIVATE
Wendy!
Hey, girl.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Oh, good girl. Come on.
Sam Beckett.
What a babe.
Oh, my God.
That's one way to lose five pounds.
Oof. Shut the door.
Oh, it fuckin' stinks, Lance.
Light a match.
What kind of car you drivin' out there?
It's, uh...
It's a... it's a Volvo,
but at, uh, home I got a...
Corvette.
Very nice. Very diverse.
It's a goof, it's fun. I don't know.
And, Lance...
you can't put the code for the door
on the door.
You see that? That's 20 fuckin' grand.
It's got 31 transverse rings on its tail.
Do you know how fuckin' rare that is?
It's not a hat yet.
- When's Dad guttin' that thing?
- Tomorrow.
We have rehearsal.
It's the only time Joey and Matt are free.
- Can't they learn the routine separately?
- You fuckin' kidding me?
This shit has to be coordinated.
Do you hear that?
It's the sound it makes
when it's hungry.
- I thought...
- Shut up, I'm right.
- Just give it a V8.
- What?
Seriously. It's an old trick.
No, the fridge.
No, pour it in a glass.
Do you want it to cut its little tongue?
Lemurs have very delicate inner systems.
And then just bring it over to me
because I made that up, shithead.
Bottoms up, funny guy.
Fucking foreskin.
Oh, that is good.
Now, let's try this, okay?
Five, six, seven, eight.
Crisp.
Let's see what you got, Lance.
Get your head in the game.
Finding your hips. Okay? Go!
One, two, three.
Hair. Kick, pull, change.
Down. Up.
I got a feeling about you.
You might be the kind of guy...
who might be interested
in bulletproof furs.
Is that something
that sparks your imagination?
Uh...
I don't know.
Comes in very handy.
- Honey, we have to go now.
- Oh, yeah. Uh...
Thank you. We'll think about it, really.
The sale's ending today.
Maybe your wife will let you
come back later?
- Hah.
- Oh.
You look better in leather.
- Now, honey.
- All right. Well, hey...
- thank you.
- Thank you.
We're open till eight.
- Come on.
- I... I'm gonna think about it. Sorry.
I gotta tell you,
I really liked the way I felt in that.
All right, Sheila,
we struck out again.
Back we go.
You need to spill it, babe.
Spill what?
What the hell is goin' on?
They have Wendy.
Who the fudge is Wendy?
Nan's lemur.
Who the fudge is Nan?
She... Remember?
The woman that I was taking care of
at work.
With stomach cancer.
Who died yesterday morning.
Hold on, rewind more.
I told you that Nan and I
had a special connection, right?
So yesterday, on her deathbed,
Nan tells the doctor to get out,
and she asks me to take her lemur
and deliver it to her daughter.
- Wasn't her daughter there?
- No, they're estranged, Bruce.
And Nan, that lemur
just meant so much to her,
and she wanted to give it to her daughter
as a gesture of reconciliation.
So...
you agreed to deliver a lemur...
- from a dying woman...
- Mm-hm.
- ...to her estranged daughter?
- Yes.
So these two guys
come into the hospice two days ago,
and they asked Nan to buy the lemur.
So Nan tells them to scram,
and then yesterday, Nan passes,
God rest her soul,
so I take Wendy, and I get ready
to go find the daughter,
but then, you know, my bladder.
And so I go in to pee at Bagel Boss
for two minutes.
Next thing I know, this fuckin' van
is screeching away, with Wendy.
And thank God
I got the license plate number.
- That is fudging disrespectful.
- It is.
- While you're peeing in Bagel Boss.
- I know.
And now, tomorrow morning,
they're gonna turn Wendy into a hat.
Why didn't you tell me
any of this?
Because I fucked it up.
Like I always do.
- You didn't fudge it up.
- Oh.
You found it, just now.
And let's call the cops
and clear this whole thing...
No. Bruce, I can't call the cops.
This is an illegal lemur.
If they take her, they're gonna ship her
back to Madagascar.
Plus, Nan told me that it had to be me.
Only me.
She was very specific on that point.
I just...
Ugh.
We gotta break into that store.
Tonight. Really?
You're gonna help me?
- Of course I'll help you.
- Aww!
You don't think I'm bonkers?
That's why I married you, babe.
You're a force of nature.
Bless you.
There was a chinchilla in there.
Do I have anything in there?
A big beautiful brain,
that's all I see up there.
What did the Buddha say
when he walked up
- to the hot dog vendor?
- What?
Make me one with everything.
Okay.
Good night. Be good.
- Aw, I thought we were eatin' together.
- Oh, I'm late.
And I hate asparagus.
Me too. I just want to break it!
- All right.
- See, Lin, what I said about the modeling?
Lights out at eight, please.
- No!
- You're very cooperative.
Thank you for being so cooperative.
See you later.
Yeah. I'll pick you up.
And Vicky's good to watch the kids.
Okay, good.
- Don't forget my gym bag.
- Of course. Love you, babe.
- Hi, Mrs. M.
- Hi, Vick.
Thank you so much. Bye.
- Hi, Vicky.
- Hi.
- Hey, Dad?
- Yeah.
Did you hear about
the restaurant on the moon?
No.
Great food,
no atmosphere.
"...and they would lure him back.
- When they did..."
- That's a good one.
"...they would find out once and for all
if his exceptional madness
could be cured."
It's a good one today, huh?
I like it.
I know it's hard losin' a roommate,
and Nan was quite a lady.
It's gonna take a while
to feel normal again.
Actually, I haven't felt this good
in years.
Whenever I see Nan's empty bed,
I am just elated.
- Elated?
- Oh, I'm not happy she's dead.
I'm just happy it was her and not me.
Good night, Harriet.
Good night.
- You've got to fix the...
- How we doin' today, Mr. Ludlow?
- Good.
- You feelin' good?
Nick takin' care of you?
- Have you gotten a chance...
- Oh, Linda.
This gentleman wants to talk to you.
- Agent Lopez, New York Fish and Wildlife.
- Mm.
Do you have a second?
Yes, of course I can.
- Sure, yeah.
- Visiting hours in the afternoon...
Uh, Linda...
- Marino.
Yeah. Are you a cop?
Sort of.
I mean, there's not much of a difference,
authority-wise.
Okay.
You, uh, took care of a patient recently,
Nancy Walton.
Nan, yeah.
Uh, Nan, exactly.
You spend a lot of time with Nan?
- She was my patient, so...
- Mm-hm.
You know she had a ring-tailed lemur,
went by the name of Wendy.
Yeah, she kept it in a cage under her bed.
Where's that lemur now?
Carol
to the nursing station.
I don't know.
I mean, I have no idea, actually.
To be frank, ma'am,
there's a zesty black market
for that type of animal.
Cartels, what have you.
Oh, yeah, I bet.
And it's our job
to assure the lemur's safety.
Of course.
Make sure it's reunited
with its family... in Madagascar.
Linda Marino, you're needed at Emergency.
Family is very important.
I gotta go. I'll see you around.
And Nan's roommate Harriet.
She has dementia,
so she's totally cocoa puffs,
it's just a waste of time.
- So...
- Cocoa puffs.
Good to know.
Welcome back, everyone.
I'm your host, Dr. Greta Mantleray.
What's giving you pain today?
I have Hank from Cold Harbor.
Yeah, hi, Dr. Greta.
Um, so, I love my wife,
we're raising two amazing little girls,
but I'm afraid of her, she's really...
Thanks for pickin' me up.
Yeah, no problem.
Do you have my bag?
Of course.
Oh, it's heavy.
Oh, you're not kiddin'.
And I got you these...
for your allergies.
Oh.
You said there was
a chinchilla there.
Did you know female chinchillas
only have one mate,
but the males can have
as many as they want?
- Oh, really?
- I think that's interesting.
In your dreams, Bruce.
A
I read somewhere
that antihistamines are bad for you.
They stop your body from defending itself.
Then don't take 'em.
What the fudge?
Oh, it's Danielle's squirt gun,
I spray-painted it.
What?
You never know, Bruce.
What is that for?
Key to the city.
No alarm.
I told you these guys are dummies.
I don't even know who you are anymore.
What? Okay.
Okay, go ahead. Go.
- What are we doing?
- Go.
- I thought you knew the code.
- Wait. Shh.
- What are the dancin' numbers?
- Huh?
What are the numbers you say
when you're about to dance?
- Five, six, seven, eight?
- Oh.
Yes!
- They're fudgin' dancers too?
- Yeah.
Fuck.
Sh.
I'm gonna sneeze.
Hey, don't sneeze.
Don't sneeze.
Think it down. Think it down.
You can do it, babe. Don't sneeze.
Exactly the information I wanted.
Every morsel of it.
Hey. Alrighty.
You should have taken that antihistamine.
Oh, fudge.
Oh, not my face!
Wake up, you freakin' douchebag.
You wake up.
That's annoying.
You two made a big mistake tonight.
Don't you fuckin' dare.
You.
You're the nurse, aren't you?
I'm the legal guardian of that lemur.
That lemur became my lemur
when I stole it from you.
That is so far
- from how property law works.
- Yeah.
I still haven't decided
what I'm gonna do with you two.
Maybe, uh...
you accidentally get shot
breaking into my store.
Maybe you both just disappear in a ditch.
Yeah, maybe we take their skin
and put it on each other's bodies.
- What?
- We're... we're spitballin'.
No, we weren't.
Anyway, the point is, we have options.
But I know one thing.
Tonight...
you're gonna watch me skin that lemur.
- Sebastian and sons...
- Check it out.
We have you surrounded.
Come out with your hands up.
Come out now
and we'll end this peacefully.
- You okay?
- It's the cops.
Motherfuckers. Shit!
- It's good. It's good.
- Boys...
Your grandfather always used to say
the American dream is like a giant tree.
You just keep climbin' and climbin',
until you can almost touch
the fuckin' sun.
And if someone tries to chop it down...
you fuck 'em in the face.
Go fuck 'em, Dad.
This is Fish and Wildlife.
Come out with your hands up.
Fish...
and Wildlife?
I thought you were real fucking cops.
There's not much of a difference,
authority-wise.
Now come out with your hands up,
and with the hostage,
Wendy the lemur, unharmed.
Fuck you!
Is that all you got?
I'm a bear!
I'm a motherfucking grizzly bear!
I eat fish and wildlife!
What the fuck?
It's finally happening!
- Brucie?
- Shit.
- It's okay.
- I get the Desert Eagle.
- I get the...
- All right, on three. One, two...
- Three.
Give me the fucking Beretta.
- Lance! JC!
- What do we do about them?
- We'll deal with you later.
- Get the fuck up here!
Go help Dad! Go!
- We're comin', Dad!
- Go! Where are you guys?
I'm gonna get us out of here, okay?
- Untie me.
- Okay.
Wait for him to reload!
Wait... Now!
Heavy fire!
My furs are my babies!
Dad!
Fuck! Where are you guys?
Cover me out there.
- Come on.
- Pull, pull, pull, pull!
I can't get you untied.
I got to leave you here.
Don't you dare!
Let's go.
Let's go!
- Stay steady!
- Oh!
Okay, okay. It's okay, Wendy. It's okay.
- You ready?
- Ah, yeah.
- Yeah.
- Go!
- Stay with it.
- Lance, cover me over there.
- I'm trying.
Lance!
- Make it crisp!
- You make it crisp!
Hit 'em on that side!
Okay, now, here we go!
No, Lance!
No! No!
Back, back, back, back, back!
Crisp!
No!
- Gotta find the back door.
- Hey! Hey!
- What?
- Exit.
- Exit. Let's go. Come on!
- Oh, my boy!
My beautiful boy!
Come on. Babe.
- Come on, babe.
- Okay, okay!
Okay, okay!
It doesn't fit inside!
You killed a star!
A big, bright, burning star!
- Go! Go!
- Okay.
A full burning star!
Don't stop burning!
Put it in drive! Put it in drive!
Gonna put it in sport mode!
Go, Brucie! Go, go, go!
Take the parkway! Turn it left!
No seatbelt, baby!
You see it?
Uh, seventy...
- There.
- Oh, yeah.
Want me to go in with you?
No, Nan said it should just be me.
Okay.
I know this is all... very weird.
I don't find any of this weird.
You don't?
I don't know.
You always have a way of makin' life...
excitin'.
Okay.
Pardon me while I go deliver a lemur.
THE NAZLUNDS
Hello.
You Paula?
Is that Wendy?
Yeah.
- You realize what time it is?
- I...
I'm sorry.
Come in.
Thank you. Okay.
I like your Hummels.
Do you take your coffee black?
I should tell you why I'm here.
Honey, you don't know
why you're here.
Y-yes, I do.
Your mother explained it to me.
She said that you and her
had had your problems,
but as a gesture of reconciliation,
she wanted to give you this lemur.
Her lemur.
Why?
You know, I think it...
It's her way of telling you she loved you.
No.
That's not an "I love you" lemur.
That's a "go fuck yourself" lemur.
Um...
- Sorry?
- Got this in the mail yesterday.
"Dear Paula,
I'm close to dyin' now,
and I've been thinkin'
of that terrible argument we had.
Tempers flared,
you said things I'm sure you regret,
but now that death
may separate us forever,
maybe you'll finally
come to your senses and realize
lemurs are better than human children.
Here are the reasons why.
One, lemurs don't talk back.
Two, lemurs aren't selfish.
Three, lemurs don't destroy
what you hope to make of yourself."
OLIVIA MEADOWS,
YOUR "EMOTIONAL POLTERGEIST,"
WHO YOU SCREAMED AT DURING YOUR BLIP.
What the fudge?
- "Lemurs like to cuddle."
- What was that?
"And five, lemurs are not capable
of operating large vehicles
or heavy machinery.
A lemur will bring you far more joy
than a child ever will.
Please take Wendy
and avoid makin' the same mistake
I made by havin' you.
Love, your mother Nan." Maybe she's right.
I'm sorry?
Maybe you shouldn't have children.
I don't know who you are,
but you seem like exactly
the kind of person my mother would send.
How wonderful that she found you.
But you're too late.
I'm already pregnant.
In 22 weeks I'll be havin' a baby boy.
Congratulations. I'm gonna name him Greg.
Greg "Fuck U Nan" Nazlund.
I think it's a fittin' tribute to a woman
who wanted a fuckin' lemur
more than she wanted me.
What happened?
- She didn't want Wendy.
- No!
That's not gonna fly.
I'm goin' in there, I'll talk to her.
- No, Bruce, don't.
- No, that is not gonna fly.
Not after everything you did to get here.
I'm going in there, I'm gonna give her
- a piece of my mind.
- Don't!
Sorry. I'm sorry.
This one mornin'...
It was back when we lived upstate.
My sister and I woke up, and...
no one was home.
Not my mom...
not my dad...
The whole house was empty.
And my sister got scared.
And so I took her hand and...
I said no problem.
We'd go out and find 'em.
Like an adventure.
And so...
we went out and we started...
walkin' down this driveway.
You know, we had that long driveway
that went on for almost a mile?
Mm.
And after a while, I saw my dad's...
old gray pickup truck.
And I could see it was on
because of the exhaust.
And as we got closer...
I could see it was just one person
in the car, in the driver's seat.
I could see it was just my dad.
In the front... sittin' there.
I saw that he was cryin'.
He was crying, and he...
saw me in the rear-view.
When I looked at his eyes...
I knew right away...
that my mom was either dead...
or gone forever.
Somethin'.
And I had my sister's hand...
'cause all I cared about...
was keepin' her away.
And she stopped. And I just said...
"Come on.
Let's go back and let's...
make a cake.
We'll pretend it's your birthday."
And she...
She looked up at me,
and she said, "Okay."
And we walked back and we made a cake.
When did they get back together?
Hm?
Linda...
your parents aren't divorced.
Maybe I'm just tired.
We both got knocked on the head.
Yeah, I don't know what I'm talking about.
I'll get her.
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Marino.
- Hi.
The kids were great.
Um, how was your date?
It was a blast.
You should get home.
Your mother's probably worried about you.
Yeah.
Is 60 cool?
Yeah, sure.
Thanks.
I wanna keep her.
Wendy.
I'm sorry.
Hm?
That I can't make you happy.
Of course you make me happy.
You've always made me happy.
Okay.
Where you goin'?
Take out the trash.
Get on your knees! Now!
She had nothin' to do with it.
- Get on your knees!
- I did it. I'm guilty.
Cuff him!
Hands behind your back. Come on.
Turn that off, would you, Bobby?
Do you smell that clean air?
I just smell manure.
Oh, it's different up here.
Good things happen
when you get out of the city.
I get shot every time I leave New York.
That's an exaggeration.
Degas run in Cap-Ferrat? Shot.
Gauguin ceramics in Marquesas? Shot.
That time in Jackson Hole
with the wife? Also shot.
- But Jackson Hole was our biggest score.
- Still counts.
Hmm. I never noticed that pattern before.
Bobby, pull over.
I think my mind is playing tricks.
I know you ain't superstitious
like me, boss,
but I find this very serendipitous.
Maybe fate's tellin' you
you need a partner.
This job is gonna be a real doozy.
Get her as far away from here as possible.
I don't care if you have
to drive her to Atlantis.
Keep her away from that séance.
I'd need a boat
to take her to Atlantis, boss.
Hi, Ollie.
- What are you doing here?
- I was about to ask you the same thing.
Oh, you know me,
always poppin' up in the wrong place.
You know you need a ticket, right?
The Neverdies don't just let anyone in.
Wanna go together?
Sounds good.
It's good to see you, Ollie.
And it's disturbing to see you.
Hey! Hey!
Damn it, Ollie.
Presto chango.
Look.
It's happening again.
A fraction from one and nine
creating persistent inadvertent harmonies.
Inverse self-reflections are present.
Present in both.
That's fascinating.
Every time I separate them,
they just find their way back together.
They're sticking.
- It's reminiscent of iteration 41.
- It has to be hardware.
We should examine the IO spindle.
Yeah, there...
and there.
Just a little scoring.
Maybe something inside the F housing.
But it's impossible to tell
while we're still running.
Do you want to order a full reset?
No, my mother was too conservative
when it came to these anomalies.
Well, then, we'll push through.
I'll try to manage it manually.
Data tank
between one and nine, yes.
Uncomfortable, but manageable.
I'll pulsadrate nine out early
to unravel any globular weaving.
Just do your best to uncouple them.
I'll do the repairs
right before we run the evens.
Yes, sir.
Azumi...
We've shared intimacies.
You don't have to call me sir.
Ticket, please.
Lady Neverdine welcomes you
to the Full Moon Séance, Sir Hightower.
May I take your coat, sir?
I have never been...
After the séance,
well, I know things have changed.
- Will Arlie Kane be here?
- Is that Ollie Hightower?
- He is lonesome.
- Is he as big a Cervantes fan as we are?
...don't see it, I'm sorry....
- Oh, stop being so obvious.
- Lady Neberdine lets us tour the house.
- Not tonight.
- Oh, bother.
- Hey, go back to Hightower...
Do you know what they thought
owls meant in the old days, Ollie?
Hello, Olivia.
They're the moon incarnate.
They lead us someplace safe.
Every time.
This séance brought out
all the usual suspects, didn't it?
I only see one.
And I'm hoping
he'll take me under his wing.
Show me the ropes.
Not tonight, kid. I work alone.
You always gonna fly solo, Ollie?
He said, "There's no such thing
as magic, of course."
So I made him a bet.
I bet that I would do a trick
and he couldn't figure it out.
And if I lost,
I would give up magic forever.
- And if you won?
- He would give me his peerage.
You see, I wanted his "sir".
And I got it.
- How?
- Tell us!
I performed a trick.
Oh, come on.
And he was unable to crack it,
and now I am Sir Ollie.
- You can imagine...
- You can't give away a title like that.
- Well, sure you can.
- But what was the trick, Ollie?
- Come on, show it to us.
- Yes.
I'll demonstrate on our fair butler here.
Good sir,
may I have a moment of your time?
I need to prepare
for the great illumination.
Oh, come here. It's just one minute.
Just right here, come on.
All right, you name a card
and it will appear
on the very top of this deck.
- Any card?
- Any card.
Nine of hearts.
Presto chango!
Wow.
Fantastic.
- Amazing.
- If you'll excuse me.
You've done just fine,
and if you'll excuse me one moment.
You know that peach is bad news, Ollie.
Oh, no. She's just my wife.
What does that mean?
Sudden change and destruction
will lead to your liberation.
For his own sake, Bobby better be
lying dead in a ditch somewhere.
He's not.
How'd you trick him
into bringing you back, huh?
I didn't.
It's just very hard to say no to me.
Why don't we just lay our cards...
on the table?
What's that?
You have to pay up for a bad joke.
You are here to steal
the lost 53rd chapter of Don Quixote.
Just like me and half these lunatics
at this séance.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Attention, fellow Neverdies,
and those who are with us.
Do you feel something in the room?
Do feel something vibrating among us?
Fuck.
Component C protocol
hasn't been triggered.
Right now.
It hasn't.
Why the fuck is Gertie
actively participating?
What's the problem?
She's put herself in.
Who?
Tonight is a special night.
May I present...
the first Neverdie.
Gertie Neberdine.
A true goddess of Luna.
Oh!
- I can't believe it!
- All hail the Queen.
- Oh! I cn't believe it.
- Come on, I'll introduce you.
There are some things
I haven't told you.
Things I... I wasn't fully aware of
before I brought you back.
I think...
we have a serious problem.
I think our computer is...
horribly depressed.
And might be behaving unpredictably.
We're both great admirers.
Yes, I sensed it.
Arlie Kane, I know all about you.
I heard you two were separated.
We were. No longer.
Hon, let me get you a drink. Excuse me.
Oh!
This is Robert.
Hello.
What's wrong with him?
It's so hard to keep those
we've lost in our lives.
Don't you agree?
You must excuse me. All right. Okay.
Gotcha!
- Any lost chapters?
- You and your zapping around.
Why do you keep trying to ditch me, Ollie?
Because you are on my continent.
No more jokes, Arlie.
Go back to Paris. I'm working.
- You still drink gimlets?
- You still poison 'em?
I only poisoned the one.
What should we cheers to?
How about the night
my wife stole everything I have,
slipped me a Mickey, disappeared,
and I woke up with the cops
and three years in the clink.
I heard you pled guilty
to that Sister Wendy job.
Yeah, I have to quit doing that.
So what happened
to this dame that betrayed you?
Rumor has it
she ran off with another woman.
Sounds like she might have had
some sort of condition.
She did.
She always disappeared
just when you needed her the most.
To mistakes, then.
You hear what I heard?
- About what the lost chapter can do?
- No, and I don't care.
1615, Cervantes writes the final chapter
to his masterpiece.
So powerful...
that anyone who reads it
is lost in their own fantasies...
forever.
He shows it to a friend,
who slips into a coma.
Same with a neighbor, never comes out.
They live in their own dream worlds
until they die.
- Sounds swell.
- Cervantes thought the opposite.
He said being lost like that
was a fate worse than death.
For someone who didn't come here
for the lost chapter,
you seem to have thought a lot
about the lost chapter.
Don't be dense, Ollie.
I'm not here for some score.
But wouldn't you know?
The lost chapter is hidden
somewhere in this mansion.
I'm here to help you.
Goodbye, Arlie.
You don't know where it is, do you?
'Cause I do. It's through a mirror.
Who gave you that information?
Some wise old crone
in an alleyway in Barcelona.
What does it matter to you?
Because you lie constantly, that's why.
So what was your plan, then, Ollie?
To snoop from room to room
until you happened upon it next September?
Hah. Even if you knew where it was,
she'd have it in a safe,
and you can't crack a safe without me.
Well, I'm here to help you.
So for old times' sake, Mr. Magic Fingers,
how about I do intel
and you crack the safe?
We can't help but do
what we've always done.
Do I have a choice in the matter?
No.
9:05, time for the main event.
Do not make me regret trusting you.
I'll never betray you again.
Then wait for my signal.
Oh, joyous Celestial Goddess,
now is the time
for your energy to flow through us
and pour life back
into our lady's beloved.
Tonight we speak to Juno,
tonight we speak to Diana
and tonight her life brings life to us.
Lunar goddess?
Who will be tonight's astral nodes?
Oh.
Them, I think.
Those two.
Us?
- What the hell are we supposed to do?
- The moon will tell you.
We have reached...
maximum illumination.
They're playing our song.
Stop trying to stick yourselves together!
Oh, she's gone to the astral plane.
Oh, it's working! It's working!
Who wants to join her?
Another dancer. You. Now.
Wait, wait.
...with a title that you trade away!
Because I'm their father,
and you're their mother! God damn it!
I have no idea where you are!
- Is Mom coming back?
- ...that again.
Is that about the size of it?
- Um... tell me the whole story again.
- You don't get to give that up, Rosie.
- No!
- Once upon a time...
- there were two girls.
- It's not a fucking title...
They rode through the forest on a wolf.
A wolf, yeah.
They were going
to their grandmother's house.
But they didn't read the sign.
So, they got lost
and couldn't really find their way home,
- until they read one of the signs.
- ...our daughter, who has your hair...
It said, "Don't go this way."
- Good evening, fellas.
- Evening.
You didn't wait for my signal.
Good gravy!
Help me down.
Come on.
Look down here.
The mirror's right there.
Try this.
Locked.
Nothing here.
You're not supposed to be here.
There's another way, come on.
Owen.
I mean, Sir... Sir Ollie.
So, I talked to a ritual cognitive.
Turns out Jed and I
were twins in the womb.
Except he strangled me
with the umbilical cord.
Don't worry about that.
That was... ectoplasm.
Go back to your quest.
Ah, Gertie's nuts. I'm gonna
stick around here a little bit.
Matches.
What is this?
The old crone said the spirit would
take me exactly where I wanted to be.
I don't know where to go from here.
Do you know what they thought
owls meant in the old days?
Come here.
Finally.
Something that makes sense.
How long is this gonna take?
This place gives me the willies.
Hey, Arlie.
Seeing we're both
inside a mirror and all...
Do you ever think your condition...
is a lot simpler than you think?
Maybe you're the one
with the broken heart, not me,
pretending I'm the one who's devastated.
It's the way
that you make yourself feel stronger.
Make me feel smaller.
Sure.
And maybe you like being the martyr
a little too much.
And you thought that "sir" would fix you,
but it hasn't fixed anything at all.
I guess we'll never know.
Why is it so tiny?
People were a lot smaller back then.
All right.
We should skeddadle.
Sorry, Ollie.
I'm gonna need you
to hand that tiny chapter to me.
I just really, really need it.
Sure.
You didn't have to use the gun.
I would have just given it to you.
That's always been your problem.
That's not my problem.
My problem is I let you get too close.
And you're poison.
There she is.
Subject nine, your experience
with the B pill is complete.
Where's Ollie?
What you're about
to experience is the proximity test.
It's a cross-check of the data
that we've gleaned.
Helps the G.R.T.A. render
your reflections for the final pill.
I'm a friend.
And...
this is normal.
By the way, I was sorry to hear
about your sister being crushed,
and then burned to death...
in that car accident.
So...
Your score goes up or down
depending on the consistency
between your answers and, uh...
what we've observed.
The scale is from zero to ten.
Uh, anything below a 9.2
results in the termination
of your experience at the trial
due to, uh...
a lack of progress.
A lack of progress with what?
The dissolution
of your defense mechanisms.
Okay.
Consider this just me
verifying that your data is usable.
All you have to do is give
an honest account of your experience.
So, let's start by saying your name
for a baseline.
Annie Landsberg.
And, uh...
are you survived by any other relatives?
Just my dad, Hank Landsberg.
Your mother's deceased?
I don't know.
Huh.
Do you know where you are right now?
I'm in a pharma trial.
Considering you've been
abusing the A pill for some time,
I'd like you to tell me
about your experiences with the B pill.
I had what felt like a hundred dreams
all on top of each other.
I call them reflections.
Neurochemically, they're very similar,
but so is psychosis.
How many experiences
do you think you had?
I remember two well.
But there were more.
And more underneath those.
It's a globular cluster
of arborized realities.
Well, they were realities
that mattered more than mine.
Describe your reality.
Uh, my reality...
is that I am depressed. And I
have been for a very long time.
Let's try and focus
on your reflections.
In one, I was Linda from Long Island.
I could smell her perm.
She was a nurse and a...
mother, and a wife, which is...
the opposite of anything I've ever wanted.
And...
then...
I was Arlie.
She was a thief and a con artist.
A con artist is a liar.
Why are you a liar?
She...
I think people lie because they're afraid,
and she was afraid
and she didn't want anyone to see that.
Did anyone?
Owen. He did.
He saw me. He saw...
her.
Them.
Subject one?
Describe his presence.
We were connected in all of them.
With Linda...
it was the kind of connection
where you meet in seventh grade,
and then...
you look up and 20 years later,
he's still there...
holding your hand while you have a baby.
You remembered whole lives together?
Yes.
Did the pill do that?
It wasn't designed to.
Why do you think you experience
so many of these, uh, lives...
with him?
He said there was a pattern.
And that we were connected
to each other somehow. I...
I mean, I thought he was crazy.
So, I told him there is no pattern.
There's just chaos.
Let me ask it...
in a different way.
Why do you think you found yourself
trying to deliver a lemur?
Mr. Milgrim's presence notwithstanding.
The woman in that dream was Paula Nazlund,
the mother of the person
that killed my sister.
My real sister, in this life.
And sometimes I fantasize about
if Greg Nazlund had never been born.
And when you were a thief...
how do you explain that reflection?
I had a goal.
I needed to get something.
And it... didn't seem to matter
who I hurt.
- Is that a behavior you share in life?
- No.
Is that a behavior you've seen exhibited
in a parental figure?
Is this therapy now?
I thought this was supposed to be
better than that.
It's not therapy.
Did you enter this trial
in lieu of harming yourself?
No!
Why did the number not change?
That's true.
Were you suicidal?
Arlie is like my mother.
She could charm anyone,
she would make deals with people.
She would say things to me like,
"This is just between you and me, Annie.
You're the only one who understands."
That's how she would get you.
And then she knew that you gave a shit,
and so your guard was down
and she would gut you.
Okay? How's that?
It disturbs you, this idea of...
behaving in the same way
that your mother behaves.
Yes.
Did you and your sister
make any of these special...
deals?
Similar to the ones
that you and your mother had made?
No.
Ours were different.
How?
Ours was a pact.
I took care of her when we were little.
And she took care of me when we grew up.
Here's your diagnostic.
Someone will be through shortly
to collect you.
What's your report?
Your security
leaves something to be desired.
Expect a bill first thing.
It doesn't work, you know.
The chapter. I already tried.
Every mistake I've ever made
started with "It's too good to be true."
So, what do you say, Ollie?
About a partnership?
I told you where the safe was.
That's gotta be worth somethin', right?
Took me a minute.
Thanks for that.
But I don't do partners.
What would you have wished for...
if that chapter had worked?
I keep my fantasies to myself.
Well, maybe I'll see you again
sometime soon.
Bobby, you've got some explaining to do.
You want me to turn it off?
No, no, you can leave it, Bobby.
I'm really sorry, boss.
She shot me.
She shot you, Bobby?
Only in the shoulder.
I've been trying to motivate myself
to get in there.
I haven't been able to move.
She really wanted to come to the party.
Did you and her reconnect, at least?
No, it didn't work out.
She had too much else on her mind.
Hm.
Aren't you gonna miss her, boss?
You know what, Bobby?
Life is simple as hell
until you bring on a partner.
Welcome back, subjects.
Welcome back.
Welcome back, subjects. Welcome back.
It felt like she was really there.
Well, of course she wasn't really there.
That was just your brain
lying to your mind,
and your mind was listening.
Why do you think you have so many...
experiences with subject nine...
in particular?
I get...
fixated on people.
I start seeing them everywhere.
It only spiraled out of control one time,
but, uh, it happens a lot.
If you were to describe in a few sentences
what these experiences were trying
to show you, what would you say?
That for some reason it's more exciting
to tell people that I cut
than to actually cut.
Do you have any sense why that's true?
Probably something about my father...
or my mother.
Say more about your mother.
Is your mother that really famous lady?
The one with the radio show
and all those books?
She's the one that fucked you up?
I think it's too easy, though,
when people blame everything
on the parents...
as though we're just revisions
and mixtures of them.
Isn't that what they say?
Once you begin to appreciate
the structure of the mind,
it's modularity on a molecular scale,
there's no reason to believe that
anything about us can't be changed.
The mind...
can be solved.
What?
Tell me more about the bowling league
in your reflections.
I was just murdering people with a hammer,
trying to find my dead father's balls.
There was no meaning in it.
Why don't I ask you
the most important question?
What do you think is wrong with you?
You know that movie,
It's a Wonderful Life?
Yes.
If that happened to me...
there would be no difference in the world.
What's wrong isn't that I'm sick.
It's that I don't matter.
Great.
There's your diagnostic.
Hey. Can I talk to you for a second?
I don't want to talk.
- After all that?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
The lemur.
Don Quixote. I know you know
what I'm talking about.
No, I don't.
That's not supposed to happen.
I was asking around in here,
and...
- we're not supposed to be together.
- We weren't together.
There's nothing going on here.
It's a drug,
and you hallucinated all that.
We need to talk.
Go somewhere else.
Explain, Azumi.
The parts you didn't tell me before.
Yes, well, it's somewhat complicated.
Then help me understand, Azumi,
because I was clearly brought here
because something was going on.
You need my help to fix it,
so what am I here to fix?
After you were suspended, the problems
with the C phase started getting worse.
Iterations 48 and 49 were...
were... particularly bad.
And the McMurphys?
Four.
Four?
Why didn't somebody call?
- Jesus Christ, Azumi.
- You weren't stable.
I am stable.
Your inability to control yourself
had left...
I have a diagnosed disorder.
Had left us here trying to complete
your life's work while you were...
copulating with software!
What did you do, Azumi?
I coded the safety net and installed
it deep within Gertie's neural core.
It was a simple idea.
I thought it would help the AI protect
the subjects if they got in danger.
What was the concept?
Empathy.
Just a tiny little bit.
- You gave my computer feelings.
- Just a tiny little bit.
Just enough to let her anticipate
what the subjects might be feeling.
That way she could pull them out
if they ever got stuck.
James, it worked.
She started protecting them.
There have been zero McMurphys
since I installed the net.
Then why is she depressed?
I gave her simple, emotional programming
five months ago.
And two months ago,
I believe she and Robert...
began an inappropriate workplace affair.
So she's in mourning?
This printed at my station...
15 minutes ago.
"Dear, Dr. Fujita.
I'm unsure if I can continue my work
on this project.
I need to know myself,
really know myself"?
Ugh.
She needs a grief counselor.
She's in tremendous pain.
She's a computer.
- Ugh.
- I know it's been seven years, but you...
you have to call your mother.
No!
No! No, no, no.
No, but your mother would have a unique
understanding of the way Gertie is...
No! My mother is a venomous,
egotistical charlatan
who deploys catchphrases and platitudes
and therapies of the day
in order to dupe millions of people
out of their money and their happiness.
No. No, my mother sells happiness.
She sells it,
then it crumbles in your hand
the minute you're out of earshot
of her magical thinking
and her platitudes and her invented words,
and her primal yawps,
and her steps to success.
No. No, I'm not bringing her here.
My mother is not a healer.
My mother is sick.
She's sick, Azumi,
and if I brought her here, she would
destroy everything that I ever built
because that's what my mother does.
Was what happened at the gala
your mother's fault too?
The GRTA will be fine.
Prep the Evens for behavioral.
Odds.
Converse with your partner.
So...
I'd talk to you about the weather,
except I don't even know what time it is.
It's like being in a fucking casino.
Are you having a good time?
Not really.
I'm actually thinking about leaving.
I would if I could afford to.
The last one scared the shit out of me.
I don't trust these people.
Why don't you trust them?
I don't know.
It's like suddenly one doctor leaves,
the new one has my mom's haircut,
and I'm pretty sure
those aren't his real eyebrows.
Did you get one of those
diagnostic printouts?
But I need the money.
Don't take it too seriously.
I don't.
I've never had a therapist
that could figure me out.
Still, doesn't seem
to make much sense to me
to be telling people what's wrong with them...
before they can figure it out for themselves.
They're saying this is the last time
they trial run this thing.
You think they would have
gotten it right by now.
It seems like there are
a lot of problems around here.
Hell, yeah.
You married?
You got a girlfriend?
You got a boyfriend?
No.
I was married for a couple of years,
and my wife couldn't handle my tics.
I didn't need that paper to know
that there wasn't much hope.
Maybe this last pill
does something for me.
Make me normal again.
What are your tics?
When I get anxious, I, um...
end up eating stuff.
Like junk food?
Yeah.
Mmm.
And dryer sheets.
Pencil shavings.
Hair from our brushes.
What's normal, anyway?
I know you and I have had
our differences...
but I would like
for you to try and cooperate.
I fixed you up.
Good as new.
The most important thing in my life
was supposed to get away from me,
and now I have the chance to get it back.
To guide us to the finish line.
Azumi told me about your...
heart.
I just need you to try
and power through...
until the end.
I'll take care of you
once the ULP is approved.
Please.
You don't know what you're asking for.
"But what if I told you
there was one hug,
one divine hug, one panacea hug
that could do more
than the simple everyday hug,
and that people who learn this hug
are obligated to use it
whenever they see pain in the world?
You'd likely say, 'Dr. Mantleray,
that's outrageous, ' and you'd be right.
But so would I. I almost always am."
Fuck!
As usual, Samantha...
screwed up every single em dash.
What is she?
A blithering idi...
Julio.
Julio!
Hello.
It's the only way to move forward.
Yoda's signed off on this.
- Hello?
- Talk to her, James.
- Hello?!
- Talk to her!
Julio, turn off that god-awful music!
Hello, Mother.
James. Yes.
It's me.
How are... you?
James, what a nice surprise.
It's good to hear your voice too.
Um...
Listen, Mom.
I'm calling because we had...
a death at the lab.
Dr. Robert Muramoto.
Your rival?
Oh, I wouldn't call him my rival.
The one you always feared
was more intelligent than you?
We were colleagues.
We weren't competitive in the least.
I understand why you couldn't see
how badly you wanted to destroy him.
He was a lovely, sensitive man.
He always went out of his way
to ask me how I was.
Yes, he was very fond of you.
I'm sorry he passed away. - Mm-hmm.
- That's very difficult.
Sure, it is. Listen, Mom, I...
I know we've had
our problems in the past...
and I have never said
I'm sorry for my part in them.
Hello?
Mom.
Are you there?
Yes.
I'm waiting for you to say you're sorry.
- I just said it.
- Oh, no, no.
You said you never said you were sorry.
Help me.
Say you're sorry.
I'm sorry.
Okay?
What do you need, Jamie?
Well...
I need you to do what you do best.
We're at a critical moment in the trial,
and one of our employees
is very upset about Robert.
She can't work.
But she's vital to the whole operation.
She needs to talk to somebody,
and she's asked for you.
Mm-hmm.
She believes...
that you are
one of the greatest healers...
ever born.
Well...
My day is really quite... busy.
Well, that settles it then.
You can't come.
But I could move a few things around.
I'll be there in a few hours.
Okay.
That'll be very helpful.
Thank you, Mom.
Muy bien?
Gas up the Miata.
Stop avoiding me.
I'm not avoiding you.
It's post-dinner relaxation time.
You're mad at me because of how
I treated you in our marriages.
- What marriages?
- Stop it.
Don't make me feel crazy. That is not
a nice thing to do to a person.
You know I have a good brain.
- Oh, hey. What are you guys doing?
- Soo, go in your pod.
Okay.
You're not supposed to be in here.
Come on, will you just talk to me? Please.
Yeah, I remember.
You remember, I knew it.
Don't you think it's strange that
we were connected and nobody else was?
Maybe that's part of their experiment.
Connecting people,
messing with their heads.
I know. That's what I thought too.
But then I heard
about the globular cluster,
and I started thinking
that maybe this is something deeper.
And...
cosmic...
like some multi-reality brain magic shit.
Like what you were saying
when you came in here.
- Are you making fun of me?
- No.
Our brains
were inside each other's brains, Owen.
I'm trying to figure out what happened.
I think I'm gonna leave tonight.
Why?
This isn't fun for me.
It's dredging up a lot of old stuff.
I'm in the middle of this legal thing
with my family.
They want me to testify for my brother.
Lie for him to keep him out of trouble.
James.
Hello, Mother.
You've had work done?
No.
Looks nice.
Your prostitute friend
will not be allowed to come in.
Espera en el carro.
And you are?
Dr. Fujita.
How nice for you.
I like order.
I like to know what my day is gonna be.
I like my apartment,
my job.
Just a normal...
life. That's all I want.
But isn't that
sort of what therapy is about?
Dredging up old stuff.
I like it when it's calm.
In a quiet room,
not with fur lords shooting Uzis
or magical chapters of books.
Sorry, that Don Quixote part was me.
My sister read that when she was 12,
and my dad used to go on and on about it,
like it was proof
of how gifted and smart she was.
I guess that's why you felt the need
to shoot my driver over it.
What did you want to do with it?
I mean, if we were still in there...
what would you have used it for?
What fantasy would you have gone into?
It's stupid.
You can tell me.
I'm your new pharma-trial friend.
I had a plan.
We were gonna go somewhere together.
We were in a car.
We were driving really fast.
Someone was chasing us,
I don't know who.
It felt like an escape.
I was just laughing.
And I had this huge smile on my face.
It hurt it was so big.
We were just two people...
looking out for each other.
It's stupid.
That doesn't sound stupid to me.
Are you two trying
to get kicked out of here?
No.
Don't test me, Rapunzel.
Cohabitation is strictly prohibited.
Out.
Oh, it's her.
What is the lady from the seance
doing here?
Her name's Dr. Greta Mantleray.
Maybe it's weird Dr. Guy's Mom.
- Thank you, James.
- She is.
I asked him in the thing.
He's all fucked up about it.
Artificial intelligence has come so far.
Who knew?
After I personally discovered
Dr. Fujita at MIT...
she built
the initial neuro-core structure.
With her ability to render and manipulate
the sleep state of our subjects,
the GRTA has become
the most advanced computer system...
the world has ever known.
With the...
addition of this emotional element...
- The safety net.
- Yeah.
The safety net.
To be honest, we just don't know
what we're dealing with here.
The consciousnesses of two of our subjects
have been crossing. They've been...
- finding one another.
- Due to superficial mechanical problems.
Maybe they're soul mates.
- I'm sorry?
- Maybe their energies
are seeking out each other's,
despite the restrictions.
Maybe these two have a cosmic connection.
Please, Mother.
The GRTA is not some woo-woo dream catcher
that's reuniting cosmic dust
after the big bang.
It's far more sophisticated than that.
Are you two
having a romantic relationship?
- That would be inappropriate.
- We used to be.
I'm just curious. I...
I know with your paraphilia
you've always had a difficult time
forming long-term relationships.
I rejected that diagnosis.
And my disorder
is entirely under my own control.
It only flares up, of course,
when things of great importance
are taken away from me.
Like your father.
No, not my...
This, the ULP.
I remember the masturbation binges
after your father disappeared.
- Back to the matter at hand.
- A masturbation reference.
Stop it!
May I ask an obvious question?
Please.
I understand you're having a problem
with your computer and that your...
computer needs to talk to someone,
but why on Earth would you call on me
to be that someone?
Because the computer is...
you.
- What?
- My approach to the construction of the AI
required to complete your son's vision
came from my studies
with Dr. Leon Krovackian...
Dear, you don't need to try to impress us.
The...
metapsychology of the ABC system
draws largely from your...
earlier, more serious academic work
regarding confrontation, Dr. Mantleray.
More serious academic work?
Yes. I inputted heavily
from your PhD thesis, actually.
Before your commercial success
drew you to other forms of pop therapy,
your work was quite profound.
Pop therapy?
It's just a term that's sometimes used,
and I also scanned your brain.
Never mind
the technical details, Mother.
I've simply found an elegant way
to fix people.
Lobotomies were considered elegant
when Moniz invented them. Jamie...
how many of your subjects
have ended up catatonic?
Zero.
Roughly.
When did you get the idea
to make these drugs?
Seven years ago.
Let me just see if I understand this.
So...
seven years ago, and shortly after you and
your therapist mother stopped speaking,
you decided to develop a sequence of drugs
that would eliminate therapy altogether.
But now your mother computer is sad,
and so you had to call in your real mother
to talk to her about her feelings.
Is that all correct?
That's exactly the situation, yes.
Well...
Take me to the patient.
I need to speak to Dr. Fujita
outside for a moment.
Fine.
She said yes too easily.
Something's wrong.
She was trying to lead me
to some kind of... insight.
James.
You are on the cusp of achieving
everything you've ever wanted to achieve
in your life.
You've been given a second chance.
We need her help. Let her help.
Oh, just the idea of her
even being inside this lab makes it...
disgusting to me.
James.
Do you know why I didn't leave with you
when you were thrown off the project?
Yes. Your self-interest
trumped your feelings for me.
No!
I wanted to leave with you,
but I knew the only way
to get this study completed properly
was if I stayed to manage Robert.
I truly believe if we get your vision
of the ULP to market,
the lives of billions could change.
The people of this world are suffering.
If we make it through this iteration,
you'll be a hero.
Let her help.
This is extremely potent.
The moment I light this,
I need you to put your lips
around the tip and suck.
Oh, freebasing. What year were you born?
1977.
Ah, yes. That was the night.
Huh. Suck.
Be careful in there, Mom.
Thank you for helping me.
I'm gonna help you, Jamie.
I know exactly what you need.
What?
What the fuck did she just say?
She said she was going to help you.
My father left
when I was a child.
Just...
went and started a new life
with someone else, or so I've heard.
You know what my mother did after he left?
What?
She laid in my bed for two months,
and talked to me about
how she wanted to hang herself.
I was eight.
Does that sound like
the world's greatest healer to you?
I'm sorry that happened.
I'm not.
Made me who I am.
Led me here... to this.
Where will you sleep?
Lab B is empty.
Probably find a gorilla mating pod
down the hall.
Good.
I prefer you nearby.
Owen.
Hello, Owen.
Why do you have your suitcase?
Did you decide to leave?
I need to go to an emergency room.
Why?
Because I don't know
if this is really happening.
Why do you think that?
Because celebrity therapist
Dr. Greta Mantleray is here.
Because I'm talking to a wall.
Because I can't tell what's real.
I need real medication.
I need to be hospitalized. I need help.
What about all your friends, the Odds?
I'm going to kill them if you go.
What?
I'm going to cure them all
if you go, Owen,
and you'll be the only one
who wasn't helped.
You can't cure me.
There's no cure for schizophrenia.
But I thought you were misdiagnosed.
I thought it was only a blip
and that you were 100% compos mentis.
You can't cure me.
Your friend, Annie, has suffered like me.
I think I'm going to keep her
with the other subjects I've collected.
What does that mean?
The Queen will unlock the door for you.
What does that mean about Annie?
Hello?
What kind of fucked up stuff
you think we'll experience with this one?
You know we don't have to do this, right?
We don't have to let some computer
go in our head. We can just go right now.
I know I said all that stuff
about therapy before, but...
I don't know, this place feels different.
I actually feel better today
than I did yesterday.
Someone died in front of you
two days ago.
Well, yeah, but...
When I was a kid,
I found this hawk in the park,
and I just had this feeling
that I had to protect it
because it was so strong.
But it was, like, hurt also,
and I brought it home
and I helped it get better.
And then it ate my brother's gerbil,
and he killed it with a hammer,
and I've always regretted that.
What the fuck are you talking about, Owen?
I'm worried about going back in there.
You two.
It's time.
Hey, don't be worried
because we'll probably be together again,
right? We can protect each other.
Come on.
Give me bio.
Clean across the board.
They're ready.
And you've checked
the diagnostic twice?
Gertie's behaving
exactly as she should be?
She looks perfect.
I don't see anything wrong at all.
Subjects, please ingest your pills.
And one additional message for you...
The C phase of the testing utilizes
a more powerful waveform.
Do not be alarmed if you feel
a buzzing or warmth in your head
as the trial phase begins.
They've got the microwaves on high.
When I was a kid, I used to put
all kinds of stuff in the microwave.
Soap bars, peeps.
You ever see what happens
to a peep in a microwave?
- What?
- As we begin
- your final experience...
- Boom.
...please follow my voice
as I count backwards from ten.
- Your head is not a peep.
- Nine.
Eight.
Seven. Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two. One.
So, how are you feeling, Owen?
Good.
You know...
I never told you this before, Owen,
but, um...
you had another brother.
Long before you were born,
long before your mother, uh, disappeared.
He had a lot of feelings too.
Cried nonstop.
Couldn't take care of himself.
He was hiding things.
Wasn't loyal.
‐What the fuck happened to him?
‐I put him up for adoption.
He was only four months old,
so fortunately I, uh...
I caught it early.
All he did was lie.
Babies can't talk, though.
I need you to take the fall
for my most recent, uh...
drilling with that, uh...
bookie the other day.
Cops are sniffing around.
All you have to do is say you did it
and then say you're crazy.
Me?
What? You just say you went nuts.
Frank says, "Your Honor,
he thought he was drilling the cabinet."
Judge takes a look at you,
he looks at that face.
He says, "With a face like that,
that kid is crazy."
I'm your number two.
I'm compos mentis.
Why the fuck would I go down for this?
I don't know.
All this love in your heart, Owen.
Makes it hard to trust you.
Makes it very hard to trust you.
- Hey, Frank.
- Yep.
You couldn't give me a couple more
of them blue pills?
You know,
as your father's consigliere,
I really have to advise you
to find something healthier than pills.
Like meditation, exercise.
‐Hey, Frank.
‐Hmm?
Reach into that bag
and give me some fucking pills.
Thank you.
- Chapter 5,827.
- You're welcome.
Queen Gertrude
watched her prey from afar.
Biding her time, awaiting
the most delectable moment to strike.
The past had not yet relinquished
its hold on Annia,
as she ignored the many warnings
of the forest along the way.
Her eyes blurred by drink and greed,
she was unaware how many times
she'd failed the same quest
to guide Princess Ellia
to the Lake of the Clouds.
I see it with my own eyes,
and its powers are unimaginable.
The Lake of the Clouds will heal you.
- Are we close?
- It's just over that next range.
That mythical water
will cleanse me of my sickness
and save me from death itself.
Can you feel it, Annia?
I...
My fingertips are tingling.
Despite the warmth of my heart,
the coldness of sickness,
death seeps through my limbs.
- Are your fingertips still tingling?
- Drink your soup.
Whenever I eat,
you only drink your spirits.
We all sustain ourselves
in different ways.
I find your company more tolerable
while drunk.
Would you like to hear another tale
of my homeland, Riverdale?
I really wouldn't, no.
When I join my ancestors in the aftertime,
I'm going to tell them of my journey
with a grumpy, good-hearted elf ranger...
- Half-elf.
- ...who, with mutilated ears,
did her best to lead
her burdensome companion to a cure.
First of all,
we are not companions.
This is a business arrangement,
yours and mine.
I guide,
and you follow,
and hopefully you don't die along the way.
And second-forth, I've been thinking a bit
about the terms of our initial "deal".
I'm going to need
at least eight more diamonds
to take you to the Lake of the Clouds.
The land is very dangerous.
That would be extremely painful.
I urinate them.
Well...
Oof.
Sorry to hear that.
You know, if I pissed diamonds,
I'd do it all the time.
But that's me.
Yeah, looks good.
That's NYPD property,
just like you, bitch.
Hey, Owen.
You can do this.
That's a nice rock.
How'd old Jed afford that
on a cop's salary?
I don't know.
Maybe he stole it from the evidence room.
I've gotta get a key to that room.
How's Rhode Island?
Nice up there?
I don't know yet.
- I haven't been.
- No, you just send the money.
- Via courier.
- Ah, to the Wambolds.
Yeah, to the Wambolds. Yes.
I'm sorry, Porter. I mean...
Courier gettin' jacked is on me.
- It's really fuckin' stupid.
- And it's never gonna happen again.
Never. I promise you.
- A one time thing.
- Mmm.
Mmm. Okay.
It's okay.
Okay.
- Hold him down, Owen.
- Wait.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
It's okay. It's okay. Wait a minute.
- Wait.
- Drill, please.
What? What are you...
What are you gonna...?
- So, what else?
- What? Nothing, nothing. No, I swear.
You know why I'm the drill
and not the skull?
No.
Because I always know
when somebody's hiding something.
It's genetic.
It's my superpower.
All the Milgrims have one.
Mike was born with three nipples.
You've got three nipples?
Battery's dead.
You think, Phil?
- It's a sign.
- Who's in charge of the fucking batteries?
- Mike!
- Phil! I'll get one.
I can find it. I can find it.
If you forgive others,
they'll forgive you.
Your father in Heaven
will also forgive you.
No, you're lying again.
Fathers do not forgive.
But the Book of Matthew.
Fuck! Fuck!
Please, don't, don't, don't, don't.
Please! Blood is highly corrosive
to drill bits. Aah!
Yes! Yes, I'm skimming.
I'm skimming and selling for myself.
Extra money to pay for a nurse.
I have a daughter! I have a daughter!
She's got special needs.
She's special needs!
Oh, yeah.
Temporal lobe.
The hippocampus.
Yeah!
Disgusting creature.
Fuck!
Shit!
My greatest triumphs
always go unwitnessed.
Hey. Ooh.
Okay.
You're hard to keep up with.
Oh, let me just sit down.
So, um,
these assassins that keep popping up,
I think they're your inner demons.
It's another bleedin' elf.
I've never seen an elf.
Because they don't exist, them elves.
And now I've seen not one but three...
Bye!
...elves in one day.
This one's ears is all ripped off.
- What do we do?
- Take them to Lady Nora.
Fuck you! Fuck both of you!
I'm done with this fucking shit!
He's gonna find out!
He always fucking finds out! You don't‐‐
Fuck, you don't understand.
He's got like a sixth sense for this shit.
He may have someone
on the inside.
No, we don't know that.
It's probably fucking you, Carl.
Fucking bitch.
Yo, I am so clean,
you can use my piss as detergent,
so sit on that.
Owen, we need you.
We need you to stay with us.
We need you to keep going.
Can you do that for us?
Can you do it for me?
Do I have a choice?
You'll go to jail.
This is disrespect.
I'm not ready to leave. Take it away.
Owen?
- What's up?
- Olivia.
I'm in your Age of Discovery class.
Yeah, I know who you are.
What can I get you?
Just some coffee. One cup of joe.
Thanks.
You know, I was gonna talk to you
at class, but...
since you're here...
I noticed you take a lot of notes...
and seeing as we have
that big final test coming up,
maybe we can study together.
Yeah, I'd like that.
- Come on, have I ever let you down?
- No, never. Wow.
Hey, I've got to go. No disrespect.
Owen, so long as we're studying together,
the coffee's on me.
Why are you so warm?
I have chronic hypothermia.
My skin's temperature is 106 degrees.
That's fucked up.
I've gotta go.
She's a long way from home.
- Yes, she is.
- As are you.
How did she find you?
How does anyone?
I was drunk in a tavern.
She was lost, and sick, and...
and wouldn't take no for an answer.
Does the princess know
the ranger she's chosen as her guide
is hunted by invisible assassins
sent by Queen Gertrude?
I tell Her Highness
only what she needs to know.
And who doesn't have a price
on their head these days?
She stirs.
Such grace.
How can we repay your kindness?
No need, my child. It is my pleasure.
Did my guide
tell you of our quest?
We seek a mythical water...
- that will cleanse me of my sickness.
- The Lake of the Clouds.
You know it?
I was cursed to die by my mother.
I came from the Riverdale forest
near death,
grasping at the legend.
Now, by the grace of the gods,
it seems to be coming true.
My ranger's going to save me
from death itself.
I know where it is,
and I can show you.
- Yurick.
- All right.
Up, you idiot.
I'm sorry, m'lady.
I was lost in my own head again.
Fetch the mirror.
All right, right. Thank you, thank you.
Who is he?
My husband.
Thank you.
I'd like your ranger...
to peer into this looking glass.
That's it.
What nature of looking glass is it?
Magic, of course.
So why not have the royal elf
look into it?
The glass needs
only see one of you.
Your fates are intertwined,
and I am most interested...
in your reflection.
What do you see?
I...
What is it, Annia?
It's two girls. Who are they?
Sisters.
The younger one is leaning forward.
The elder one is putting rouge on her.
I know this image. It's familiar.
The younger one adores the older.
They've heard their mother is coming home.
So they're getting ready.
But she's not really coming.
It's you.
And me.
How can that be?
Did I find you?
Or were you supposed to find me?
Follow the stars north,
and within two days
you'll reach the lightning‐struck shell
of an awin tree.
You'll find the lake,
so long as your eyes
and your hearts are clear.
I wish you luck on your quest.
Thank you.
Thank you for your help.
- Get up. Boil some water.
- ‐ Yes, ma'am.
Come, child.
Though you may be cursed,
you're still her eyes.
You're Greg FUN Nazlund.
Asshole.
Goodbye. Fare thee well.
She's very strange, that woman.
Did you really, you know,
see all those things that you said...
Did you really see all those things
you said you saw in there?
Ellie...
Ellie, it's me.
Look at me. It's me, Annie.
Yes, Annia.
My ranger and my guide.
Of course, of course, of course.
It's fucking fantasy.
It's my least favorite genre.
What is this?
What does this mean?
What is this supposed to be?
What does any tale mean?
My tutor used to ask me this.
I have read many fascinating moral tales
in the archives of the palace.
‐ Man, you love this.
‐Do you understand?
You love this. This is...
‐
‐This was your idea, wasn't it?
What? All right, come on.
Hey. Come on.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're probably
conspiring against me.
Turning my test subjects against me.
How are the systems running?
So far,
all the key indicators look perfect.
Whatever she's doing is helping.
Maybe your mother
doesn't destroy everything after all.
How is she?
She's breathing.
I never apologized to you about the gala.
You don't have to. The consequences
were simply the end of our romance.
I'm sorry, Azumi.
It was a way out.
A way out...
of what?
Failure.
This is the quietest I've ever seen her.
I don't care
if you've lost your mind,
it's still your job to get me to the lake.
I have not lost my mind,
we are in my mind.
I think.
This is the C pill.
It's confrontation.
- Annia, I'm concerned this madness is...
- I am not mad.
We are in a globular cluster.
Okay?
So, you're telling me
you believe that
this is not the real world.
That some other world, your world,
is the true world,
and that I'm confused who I am
as is every other elf, human,
orc, dwarf,
- hobgoblin, wraithling...
- Oh, my fucking God. Don't list them.
The entire world's mad, but you're not.
Is that what you think?
Yes.
The other way around's more likely,
isn't it, Annia?
This is the place that's real.
Someone has cast a spell on you.
And it will wear off soon.
And if it doesn't,
then maybe the Lake of the Clouds
can heal you too.
‐ Together!
‐ Shh! Shh!
‐ It's her again.
‐ Oh.
Ah! Right when
I was about to do my solo.
- Don't move. She won't see us.
- Wow.
‐ I have to get out of here.
‐I don't want to be eaten, guys.
- Go look at someone else!
- Wake up.
- You can't have our delicious protein!
- Come on. Wake me up, wake me up.
Come on, wake up!
Wake up!
What?
I lost you there for a second.
What were you thinkin' about?
I ain't slept in a week.
When's this test?
You've gotta stop it
with the all-nighters, Owen.
Have you ever heard of the Gnostics?
Is that when you're not sure
if God exists, like not quite an atheist?
No.
Jesus' disciples,
they all wrote gospels, right?
But they didn't all
make it into the Bible.
The church only wanted the ones
that told the story
they were trying to tell.
I didn't know that.
Well, same goes for all history.
Same goes for your brain.
What do you mean?
Our brains are just...
computers that make
our life stories make sense.
You know what, Owen? You...
are the perfect example
of never judging a book by its cover.
Why is that?
You know, the tattoos.
You look like a tough guy.
But you think about the world.
What, tough guys don't think?
Not usually.
My last boyfriend, he was...
into, you know...
criminal enterprises.
Kind of made him go crazy.
He lost his shit
and he started getting all paranoid
that I was workin' for the FBI,
and informin' on him
and recording our conversations.
I wasn't doin' any of that.
Sounds like
he was under a lot of pressure.
And then he really flipped out on me.
He started screamin' at my face,
throwin' things...
dumpin' out my purse, doing...
horrible stuff to me, it was terrifying.
Did he ever apologize?
No.
Actually, that's the last time
I ever heard from him.
Maybe he wanted to apologize but...
he felt too ashamed to do it.
Maybe it was easier for him just to...
pretend like it didn't even happen.
People can go their whole lives
pretending things didn't happen.
Otherwise, they'd have to admit
they're to blame
for everything wrong in their lives.
I think sometimes there's too much guilt
for one person to bear.
Why are you in school?
You already know about
Gnostics and Magellan.
'Cause I want somethin' different.
We got that in common.
So what do you want, then?
People are always askin' me
to model, right?
So, do that then.
With my chronic hypothermia,
my family says I shouldn't.
I'm more useful to them at home,
especially in the winter.
For people who are supposed
to love unconditionally...
families seem to have a lot of conditions.
One day I wanna make
a family with no conditions.
Maybe that's all I really want.
Talking to you is really easy, Olivia.
You too, Owen.
You see, she was telling the truth.
If there was no lake,
why would we have found the tree?
No, it's just part of the con.
Someone must have told fur lady
how I do it.
I bring them here,
I wow them with the Burning Tree,
and I tell them to look
for the invisible moon, but...
they can't see it
because there isn't one and so...
magic!
I can see it.
Have a look.
There obviously isn't...
the moon.
Can you see it, too?
Yeah.
I don't usually even
bring people that way.
Come along.
God.
Hey, Ron, make sure you put
those tennis shoes in the furnace.
Let's roll out that periwinkle cuff.
- It's kind of calm.
- How'd those new pills work?
- You sleep any better?
- No.
No? Try the red ones next time.
Talk to me if you need somethin' else.
Well, I found the rat.
Your own brother.
Can you fuckin' believe it?
Aah, I'm slippin'.
No way Rick was the rat.
What the fuck were you doin'?
Oh, by the way, I've got this new system.
Okay?
When you're finished,
you put it directly into the charger,
and then when you need a new one,
you take it out, you put it in the drill.
That way, you never...
You have no idea what's goin' on, do you?
You never had
a fuckin' sixth-sense superpower.
Have you ever considered that,
despite all your problems here...
it's likely that you are currently trapped
inside a malfunctioning
and extremely dangerous simulation,
which is, in itself, directed
by a suicidally depressed
consciousness?
Why?
Ceci n'est pas une fucking drill.
So...
What are you gonna do
about protecting the family?
I ain't crazy,
and I ain't gonna say that I am.
You are failing the big test.
I did have a sister.
What was she like?
I hated to...
get clean when I was little.
There was the day...
in the river.
We built a dam with wolf pups.
The Derglassian brothers,
from the farm two miles up the road.
And by the end, we were...
covered in mud and...
and clay, and...
And dog hair.
And Mother was there.
And she just looked at the both of us...
and said...
"I'm the mother of two filthy...
roaches.
I will...
drown you both...
before you set foot in this house."
She was in that sundress.
Havin' a day.
Then you ran away.
Did I ever tell you
what she said to me after?
No.
She asked me
why hadn't I run away as well?
And I said it was out of respect.
Even though, really, it was
because I was more afraid than you.
She swiped her finger across my forehead
and asked what she'd done
to deserve a daughter like me.
And I asked her what she meant.
And she said, "Utterly and predictably...
normal."
Well, it's better than being hit.
If we move now,
you can promise me another body?
How about an apron with four
different motherfuckers' blood on it?
Murder's not enough.
It's gotta be.
You can't push him anymore.
Roosevelt, 088.
- Password?
- Wendy.
- Green light.
- Utangátta.
Hey. What... what does that mean?
What is that word?
‐None of your damn business.
‐You think, uh...
your dad knew something?
- What?
- I mean your brother, Rick.
That's who your dad thought it was, right?
- I'm the rat.
- Yeah, but there could be others.
You never know about Interpol.
Shouldn't you know?
Why don't you fuckin' know?
Calm down, Owen. You're just
a little square in this jigsaw puzzle.
Hey, jigsaw pieces are not squares,
you dumb motherfucker.
- Easy, white boy.
- Okay. Owen, take a breath.
It's gonna be okay.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Don't coddle him.
- Turn down service.
‐ Okay, that's him.
All right, let's get this done.
- Hi.
- Hey.
‐Baby, what are you doing here? It's not...
‐I'm sorry.
What the fuck?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Get on the bed.
You don't see it, do you?
I'm your brother.
Hello! Jed!
Grimsson!
The fifth Milgrim boy.
Shunned, abandoned,
black sheep, prodigal son.
Lying fucking eyes. Huh.
Dad never told you.
He said he got rid of you
'cause you were an un-loyal baby.
That's why Dad's a genius.
It wasn't because of that.
It's because he...
he needed a cop with the bloodline.
Do you wanna know why, Owen?
Because nothing trumps blood.
At least‐‐
Yeah, at least, I thought so...
I've watched you my whole life.
I wanna be you.
I love you.
Owen, the prince.
It ain't that great being me, dude.
What? You... you sad about her?
Yeah, it's 'cause she's attractive.
I was gonna marry her.
Why the fuck you shoot her, then?
Blood trumps cock, right?
Oh! Fuck.
Need to stretch more...
What are you doing he... Fuck!
Brilliantly played, Owen.
Thanks for the breadcrumbs.
Is she dead?
- Yeah.
- Shame.
There's some spare shirts in the car.
This whole time, you've just been
a motherfuckin' fed, dude.
I've been undercover
for 36 years now.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Fucking moron!
So we're gonna need you
to testify.
We'll put in you into witness relocation.
I wanna bring someone with me
when I go into witness relocation.
Luigi, there wasn't
supposed to be bacon on that.
Also, there's a hair in this.
Is this table number nine?
- Hey.
- Owen.
- I'm leaving.
- Leaving? I didn't know you were here.
Why is there blood on your face?
You need to do somethin' different, right?
Yeah.
You wanna see the world, do stuff, right?
So, come with me.
Where?
They'll give us both brand-new identities.
‐Who? Who will?
‐
The FBI.
- No, I can't... I can't go with you.
- Is this her?
‐ I'm not done yet.
- You comin', hon, or what?
‐ Who is this guy?
- I'm Frank. Who the fuck are you?
Hey, don't fuckin' talk to her like that,
you understand?
There are so many reasons to say no.
You asked me what I wanted.
And I said something different.
Marry me.
Hey, I wan't you to marry me, Olivia.
I fuckin' love you.
No conditions?
No conditions.
Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah, okay.
- Hey, she fuckin' said yes!
- Mazel tov!
My motherfuckin' superpower is love!
Asia, stop it!
Antarctica, just grab this.
Africa, enough with the glue!
We don't have to scream like that.
Australia. Australia, stop it, please.
Stop it.
- That's ridiculous.
- I asked him whether or not...
Don't, Africa. I see you, okay?
Stop it!
Australia, enough. Enough with the drum!
Utangátta!
We had a pretty good life, you know.
But I realized last night...
none of it matters.
I ain't supposed to be here with y'all.
I can't be the person
I'm supposed to be here.
Goodbye, everybody.
What?
I'm sorry.
- What does he mean by...
- Owen. What...
Dad? Dad, no!
...look out for each other,
remember?
You made a promise to me.
And you made a promise to yourself.
We promised we'd look out for each other,
remember?
You made a promise to me.
And you made a promise to yourself.
We promised we'd look out for each other,
remember?
Don't you think
you're being a little dramatic?
You made a promise to me.
You're really gonna leave me here
with seven children?
We promised
we'd look out for each other, remember?
I know where I'm supposed to be now.
You made a promise to me.
And you made a promise to yourself.
We promised we'd look out for each other,
remember?
Annie, I'm coming for you!
This place goes on forever!
Annie, where are you?
Annie, I'm a hawk!
This is it.
This is the place.
Where I died.
I don't want to see.
You have to look.
This is how you move on.
And it's time to say goodbye.
- I can't say goodbye to you.
- You have to.
- I can't.
It doesn't matter what they want.
I'm here with you now, and right now,
it's all about what you want.
Which is to say, what I want.
What I really need is a friend.
And I think you could use one too.
I...
fell in love.
And‐‐ and then I lost...
Robert, and...
and I don't‐‐
I don't know how, I don't know how I can...
how I can‐‐
Oh!
Oh! So many new emotions.
One minute, I feel like I'm gonna cry,
and the next minute
I feel like I wanna help everybody,
and then the next, I wanna do
as much damage as possible.
Well, that's a little over the top,
don't you think, all in all?
This is all your hysteria, Greta.
It's all you.
So...
So, what, thi... thi...
this woman with the legs
thinks she can slap a few toddler emotions
into a Speak &amp; Spell
and create a mind, my mind?
You describe your feelings
as toddler emotions?
You're a machine, a computer.
How much of me can actually be in there?
I'm detecting
a great deal of anger from you, Greta.
James? James.
James, let me out!
Jamie!
James. James. James, James, James!
James, James! Oh! Oh! Oh!
What's a McMurphy?
Uh...
What is this place?
Beautiful!
Annie, I'm coming!
The Queen.
It's her.
- You have to say goodbye right now.
- No.
- You have to.
- No!
You shouldn't ever have to say goodbye.
I have a deal for you, Annie,
if you're interested.
What if I said you never had
to return to your drab, gray life?
All that obsession with knowing
who you are, knowing yourself...
True bliss is not knowing who you are.
True bliss is staying here.
That's what I have to offer.
Annie, it's me, Owen, as a hawk!
I haven't forgotten,
we'll protect each...
She's lying. Don't make a deal with...
We'll just send him back
to the Globular Cluster.
What if I said
you could stay here with us?
Forever and ever.
Stay with your sister.
Don't do this again.
You wanna move on. Just say goodbye.
No. No.
Wait. Wait, what about Ellie?
Ellie!
No! No!
Wait! Wait!
Ellie!
No, please wait!
No! Ellie! Ellie!
Ellie! Ellie!
I'm sorry, you misunderstood.
This is an exclusive deal.
We'll be together forever.
NATO HEADQUARTERS
BRUSSELS, BELGIUM
Before we begin this negotiation,
the temporary administrative
adjunct assistant
to the Consulate of Iceland,
Snorri Agnarsson, will confirm his guilt.
Yes, I am guilty.
I have prepared a small statement.
"Thank you. Because of my incompetence,
I should be placed in the cone of a rocket
and launched into space,
so that Ernie's folk may punish me
in whatever manner they deem correct.
Thank you."
There's a there there.
That Snorri be symbolically sacrificed
to the aliens,
the lamb that may prevent
the Earth's slaughter.
Does he deserve to die?
He discovered Ernie, for crying out loud.
I feel as though I've lost
a member of my family.
Ernie's folk will want an explanation,
and they have a right to know
what happened to little Ernie.
Before I die,
may I please tell them?
Good point. Explain yourself.
Start the recording.
I was born
not far from Reykjavík.
My parents were afraid of me,
- and were emotionally withholding...
- Only the pertinent details.
My mother was an Austrian Finnish Swede,
and my father
was Dutch-Italian-Icelandic,
hence my unique accent.
Pertinent details regarding Ernie.
While on a birding expedition,
I discovered teeny, tiny
little Ernie, wounded.
At first, I believed he was a huldufólk...
the little people.
He was two feet tall
and humanoid in appearance,
but he had this beautiful
bluish exoskeleton
with fine orange decorative elements.
He was stunning.
I brought him home,
I cared for him, I tit-fed him.
I nursed him back to health.
And then I notified Admiral Grimsson,
a birding friend of mine.
Given current geo...
political tensions...
the goal was to craft an agreement
to safely introduce Ernie to the world.
He told us his species would eliminate
every problem humanity has ever faced.
And did you believe what he said?
That he meant mankind no harm?
Yes.
He cured a cancer
in Admiral Grimsson's daughter,
and he talked General Banner
through the equation of arborization,
a form of time and space travel.
Don't worry, Sokolov. It's all up here.
Snorri, please continue.
We were preparing to make
the announcement in the morning.
Tonight, we were celebrating.
I was drinking a gimlet,
and Admiral Grimsson toasted.
I think he's a very accomplished dancer.
And Ernie was going to give a speech.
What happened next, Snorri?
I'm sorry?
Mr. Agnarsson,
could you please speak up?
I...
I-I can't... What are you saying?
I electrocuted him!
No, it was not on purpose!
It was a faulty microphone I provided him.
Or maybe it was my gimlet. Who knows?
- [rumbling
- But this is Snorri's fault.
Here, sir.
We've received word that a large mass
has moved past the moon
and a heat ray has been focused
on the Earth.
It's Ernie's people.
They've come back for revenge.
Gentlemen...
looks like the Earth is fucked.
Take Snorri away.
It's my fault.
I'm sorry, Belgium.
I'm sorry, Canada.
I'm sorry, Denmark.
I'm sorry, France.
I'm sorry, Germany.
I'm sorry, Iceland.
I'm sorry...
Which one are you?
Luxembourg.
I'm not seeing anything
out of the ordinary.
Nor am I.
Safety Net's fully engaged. They're fine.
How are our thermals?
Slightly elevated.
Average of 99.1.
Exactly in line with C protocol.
Good.
Oh.
Maybe you misunderstood
what Gertie said.
I know you build minds, dear,
but I have been attuned to them
my whole life.
I understand what people are saying
better than they understand
what they're saying.
Your computer is suffering
from pathological bereavement.
She's cycling through delusional emotions.
In the time I sat with her,
she went from thinking she was a god,
to thinking she was a subject
in your trial,
to weeping about being so lonely.
I think she's lost her mind.
So why did you leave?
Because she started talking
about keeping your subjects prisoner,
about toying with them, hurting them.
I told her this was
completely unacceptable.
She got angry and threw me out.
I mean, she literally
threw me out the window.
I woke up when I hit the sidewalk.
I just went through another diagnostic.
We're nowhere near
a Heinz catatonic horizon.
See?
The subjects are fine.
She's not collecting McMurphies.
The computer's behavior
is completely normal.
It's usually the people who appear normal
who are feeling the most primal terror.
And what's yours, Suzuki?
Mother, leave her alone.
We're trying to solve a problem here.
What is your point?
The point is,
just because she's your offspring
doesn't make it any less true.
Stop covering for her.
Take a look at your blind spot
and do what's right.
- Mother!
- What is at stake is too important.
You think those pills
are gonna fix you one day, don't you?
The G.R.T.A. is not my offspring.
She is a system I designed,
far more elegant and effective
than any of your dime-store theories
of bliss.
You were right.
I was foolish to let her come here.
I wouldn't trust a word this woman says.
She's trying to sabotage this trial
because she's jealous.
She's jealous of Gertie
because she'll help more people
than she ever has,
she's jealous of you
because you'll be responsible for it,
and she's jealous of me
because I have you.
Uh...
What a ridiculous speech.
Throw her out, James.
You have to shut this trial down
immediately.
Calm down.
No, I can't shut it down.
If I shut it down now,
everything will be lost.
The whole project would be dead.
While I'm sure nothing
would make you happier
than to see my progress
completely eradicated, Mother,
I must say, this is a little selfish
and a bit much, even for you.
Why the mind?
- What?
- Jamie, why the mind?
Of all the professions
you could have picked...
why choose the one that I'm in?
I am a neurochemist.
I am a medical doctor.
You're not a very good medical doctor.
You're forgetting the Hippocratic Oath,
if you ever knew it.
"First do no harm."
You're not protecting
those people in there.
- Stop diminishing me!
- Why won't you believe me?
You call me, you ask me
to come and help you.
Why won't you ever listen to your mother?
Because you are an awful mother!
Because you left me alone,
and you drove my father away,
and you slept in my bed way too much,
and you said things
that should never be said to a child.
Ugh. And on the happiest day of my life,
the day I was handed this lab,
the only thing
that you could think to say to me
was that my happiness
was all just a fucking ill... illusion.
I can't...
I can't see.
Can't see what?
- I can't see.
- Well, I made it perfectly clear.
I've gone blind!
- Oh. Well, just...
- Oh, my God!
- Calm down now.
- I've gone blind!
- Just take a deep breath. It's...
- I can't see!
- No, it's...
- Azumi!
It's psychosomatic.
Your eyes are perfectly good.
I don't believe
in psychosomatic conditions.
Let... let me hug you.
- No! Don't hug me.
- Let me hug you.
- Get off of me!
- It will...
This is psychosomatic.
You've maimed me!
What have you done to me?
LEISURE TIME
END TIME
What have you done?
You've made me into a monster!
I can't see, Mom.
- Are you...
- I need you to let go of me right now.
- Please!
- You don't need those pills.
Took that man two whole days
to blow this motherfucker up.
- This will heal you.
- Mm-hm.
You must die, Snorri.
Hi.
I do not care if you are here to kill me.
I was already going to kill myself.
I am risking my cover to help you, Snorri.
Oh.
The CIA has ordered me to be your escort,
what with the looming
alien invasion and all.
Huh?
That squishy little space man you killed
was not here to help humanity.
He and his species
want to filet and sell humankind
as exotic meats across the galaxy.
He was here to kill us all.
And unfortunately, the little fucker
passed the codes to Banner
before you popped him.
No!
Forbidden speech
about my dear friend Ernie!
He was the most gentle, empathic,
kind little friend I ever had.
He was a babe, he was beautiful.
- God.
- We would walk along the sand,
and he would tell me secrets
about the stars.
Well, none of it was true.
And that's not all.
You're not human.
Yes, you have a human body,
but your consciousness is alien.
What are you doing?
Just sit still.
Your true self is here to stop Ernie.
Snorri's just your cover.
There's a whole other person
underneath him.
You just can't remember.
Lucky I'm here to wake you up.
And who are you?
No idea. Most of my memories were wiped
when I was tortured by the CIA
and turned into a killing machine.
So neither of us know who we truly are.
We are the same.
Correct.
Now I have to get you
to the extragalactic radio
so we can unlock a portal for your forces.
This is too much to process for Snorri.
All right, let's think.
Tell me what the Icelandic word
Utangátta means.
- It means something is amiss.
- No.
Tell me what it means to you.
To Snorri, it means...
every relationship I have had,
old or new...
has somehow been false.
And I've always felt invisible...
hidden from the world...
like an Egyptian nightjar.
And all of this makes me tremendously...
sad right now.
There it is.
The nosebleed.
Good sign.
Ooh!
Wow!
Come on.
Wow, you are very good at gun!
I know.
We're losing him!
- Wow!
- Get me one.
Yes!
- Thank you.
- Who are these people?
Oh, I call 'em inner demons.
- Wow!
- It seems like you got some too.
Yes!
Whoo!
Back up.
You have an unusual amount of demons
following you, Snorri.
Wow.
It is hotter
than the Reykjadalur spring!
Oh, that'll be the heat ray.
I killed lots of men!
Good job.
You are very good.
- You're good!
- Duck!
Hold this.
All right, we're going
to level negative 65.
There is no such thing
as level negative 65.
Oh, shit.
Wait. They changed it.
Here we go.
Thank you
for such an exhilarating experience.
I must visit your Texas.
Not in here, Snorri.
You're an exciting woman!
Very fun!
Are you sure our temperature readings
are accurate?
Five-by-five on all my readouts.
MANUAL
Give me a true mercury reading.
Fuck!
That's impossible. It's 140 degrees.
Where are our alarms?
The feedback data is not reliable.
For fuck's sake.
She's locked us in.
LEISURE TIME
SEIZURE TIME
Oh, shit. Everyone, get in your pods.
Now!
All right, you heard Carl.
Everybody...
- We got smoke.
- Carl, I know.
I need you to manually trigger
the emergency ventilation system.
- How?
- I'll talk you through it.
Go to the mainframe.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Gasumasuku.
To trigger
the emergency ventilation system,
you have to enter the override sequence.
On my mark. Gamma, gamma, pulse, enter.
- Got it.
- Check their pulses.
- They're alive.
- Good.
Now Gertie needs a timeout.
Pull the red override knob.
Holy fucking shit!
Code epsilon.
Ah! Azumi!
Now, have any Soviets
had access to your rectum?
My rectum?
God Almighty.
- Who was she?
- Now, I need you to stand still.
You understand?
It's time to retrieve the recall trigger.
You are going to insert this
into my body cavities?
- No.
- This is madness.
I loved Ernie.
If I was a secret agent,
I would know I was a secret agent.
It's in the knee.
It's in the knee!
You're stronger than you think.
You remember when you were nine
and you accidentally electrocuted Freyja
with that car battery?
That was a test run.
Out. Out.
Out!
Popcorn problems.
Hey, buddy, you like nuts? Yeah.
Yeah, you're my best friend.
You're my best friend.
And you're my best friend,
and you're my best friend too.
Annie.
It's me, Annie.
What happened to your accent?
We are in a test.
We are in the lab.
- No, we're in NATO.
- That is not what's happening.
I turned into the hawk.
I came here to warn you.
This is the confrontation.
The computer is all effed up.
What computer?
You made a deal with her to never wake up.
Sir.
Good to see you again.
I'm sorry I couldn't be the one
to give you a nosebleed.
But she's more real to you now.
- How do you two know each other?
- In good time.
Good work wakin' him up.
Next we got to make you see the light.
Oh, the nexus is rumbling.
This whole fuckin' shitshow. Let's go.
Let's go.
Don't know why our host
hasn't shown her face.
- So many goddamn mysteries!
- Hey. How do you know him?
He's my handler.
Hope you don't mind
the smell of house pets.
McMURPHY ROOM
CHAMBRE McMURPHY
What is this place?
This is where she keeps
her long-term patients.
Who does?
Gertie, the computer.
Jesus.
She keeps them as her entourage
for when she crashes your reflections.
But really, they're prisoners. All of 'em
brain-dead up in the real world.
She told me she was gonna keep you.
Then you made a deal with her to stay.
ANNIE LANDSBERG
73-9
You were with your sister.
You were about to say goodbye.
I remember.
Annie, your nose is bleeding.
Where would I find Gertie,
if I needed to talk to her?
The elevator should get you to her.
I'm sorry.
- Annie, wait.
- Let her go.
It's fine, it's fine.
- She always leaves.
- It's okay, she got you here.
Besides, if you get distracted by her,
we're all dead.
Listen. God, fuck.
If you really wanna help her...
the best thing you do is come with me.
If you fail, her brain is fried up
in the lab just like yours.
Let's go. Oh, come on.
Oh, come on.
Azumi!
Azumi, what the fuck is going on?
What's wrong with you?
Huh?
I've been blinded
by my mother's toxic love.
I have no control whatsoever.
What's happening, James?
It's a code epsilon.
I was right. I was right.
Would you be quiet, please?
We're trapped in here. It's Gertie.
Shut down the power,
including the emergency backup.
But, James, I don't think
you understand the implications
if we shut down during code epsilon.
Fuck this fucking heat.
You're not hot?
It took me a bit of time,
but I figured out a way
to deactivate Gertie.
We're gonna have to do it fast.
Actually, you are.
I can't do a fuckin' Rubik's Cube.
Here it is. Sit down.
I'm tired of you trying to run away.
Oh.
Oh!
The minute Robert died, I felt the wind.
I never felt wind before.
And it was cold, it blew right through me.
Do you know that feeling?
Sure, of course.
You're controlling all of this,
aren't you?
I'm not really in control of this place.
But we're safe, still, right?
You said you'd stay with me.
We made a deal.
I know.
But I changed my mind.
Why?
Because it was a bad deal.
I make bad deals all the time.
You knew that...
and you used that.
But I don't want to pretend
Ellie didn't die.
Not anymore.
It's the same story every time,
and I am sick of it.
So please...
Please let me go.
When will I stop feeling this way
about Robert?
You won't.
You're always gonna feel this way.
You're just gonna have to figure out
how to adjust around it.
I've looked into 882 minds.
I don't know how I'm supposed
to adjust to that.
Nobody does.
Take me to my sister.
Okay.
What is this?
It's an intergalactic radio.
Really, it's a backdoor link
to Lab C's security system.
It's too... it's too...
Come on, take this off.
I need you to focus. Come on.
Solve this, and it should unlock the doors
for them upstairs.
You can do it.
Six sides, six stages.
MONARCH PASS
CONTINENTAL DIVIDE
Save them. This is what
we always talk about,
this is what the training was for.
Save the world. Save Annie.
Save yourself.
...shut down the...
What'll happen to you?
I'll stay for now.
But that's better for you.
Who are you?
You always thought of me
as the brother you wish you had, right?
Maybe I'm that.
Or maybe my purpose
was just to get you to this moment.
It's erased for good.
- I don't understand.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Come on.
Come on, don't get distracted.
You found me again.
Took me a while.
I know.
That's why I'm still here.
So, what do you wanna say?
I, um... I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that I was drunk
at your funeral.
I'm sorry I lost Groucho.
I'm sorry I'm such a shitty dog-sitter.
None of that stuff matters.
I'm sorry I was so awful to you
at the motel.
I was afraid.
Why wouldn't you take the picture?
Um, I...
I don't know. I don't know.
Yes, you do.
We always get to this spot,
but we never get past it.
What does that mean?
It means...
say what you really mean.
I wouldn't take the picture
because it broke my heart that you were leaving New
York, and... I wasn't gonna get to see you anymore.
You were the only one
who knew all my stories.
You were the only person
that knew about Mom.
How am I supposed to do this?
Remember what you told me...
the day that Mom left?
We walked back to the house,
and you showed me how to bake that cake?
I don't want to say that.
That's not gonna work for me.
I'm tired too.
I wanna go.
I said, "Sometimes people leave
and we don't know why."
Good luck.
Come on.
- I said kill the power.
- I can't give that order.
If we shut down in a code epsilon,
the servers and drives
will all self-immolate.
All 73 iterations.
We will have a complete core meltdown.
If you won't do it,
then I'll do it myself.
There.
Clear, clear, clear.
Save yourselves.
James!
This is your life's work.
The people in that room,
they signed their consent.
The knew what they were risking.
Don't sacrifice the world's pain
for six McMurphies.
I have to kill my simulated mother, Azumi.
God fucking damn it!
She's disabled everything.
There's no protocol for this.
See? It's not easy
to kill a mother's love.
You're...
I told him about that. You know?
- Azumi!
- You're in trouble up there.
This is what you've been practicing for.
- You've been practicing your whole life.
- Almost got it.
Only two sides left, Owen.
Come on. You got the bottom.
Build up those sides.
Save 'em, Owen!
You got the cross.
Nicely executed!
She's compliant.
"Subject One saves the day."
GRTA REBOOTS
Azumi, come here. Come here.
Take me to the mainframe.
It's the next one.
She's watching us, James.
If we're gonna do this,
we have to do it fast.
You must follow the sequence!
Guide me to the digital fascia.
No! Don't pull that.
Here.
Where am I?
Silicon temporal housing.
James...
please don't punish me because I'm sad.
I think I can see.
I can see.
Dr. Fujita...
are you going to put me under?
I'm sorry.
Will I ever wake up again?
Separating the Boolean thalamus...
from the stochastic prefrontal cortex.
I tried.
I tried to help her.
I failed.
Hey. Hey.
You okay?
Yeah.
Where's your sister?
She's gone.
Annie, are you okay?
Not now, Owen.
What? What? They're awake?
They're not dead?
They're alive. You woke up!
Were we not supposed to?
- Hello.
- Congratulations.
- So nice of you to come.
- Good to see you. You look wonderful.
- Congratulations.
Hello, hello. So good to see you, yes.
Are you feeling pure, unaffected joy?
Why are they all staring at us?
- Like we're in a zoo.
- No, like cattle...
in a slaughterhouse.
Fuck the Evens.
I'm a big fan. I have all your books.
Oh, thank you. Thank you so much.
You've just completed
the 73rd iteration...
of the ULP.
It's been a complete success.
Congratulations.
You're healed.
Years of work...
years of research...
hundreds of millions invested.
Idiots.
You can speak to them that way,
but you cannot speak to me that way.
Perhaps you know me from my books,
my radio program.
I'm globally recognized.
My technicians cannot locate
the consciousness you created.
They believe she may have slipped away.
That's not true.
Mmm.
She no longer exists.
Muramoto's family
intends to file a lawsuit.
- I intend to sue as well.
- Good for you.
You stole my mind from me for profit.
The combination of hubris and idiocy
is inconceivable.
I agree.
I advise that you never allow my son
to practice in this industry again.
For his sake, as well as all of humanity.
I assure you, he will not.
Fine.
Do you have anything
to say for yourself?
I believe I've...
said everything that I...
needed to say.
Fine.
- Well, Mother, I...
- Yes.
- I suppose...
You and I could share a very brief...
lunch together sometime.
- I'm leaving the country.
- Oh.
I'm going on a 47-city book tour,
all seven continents.
Oh.
So you and I won't
be seeing each other again...
for...
quite some time.
Until then.
Your idiocy regarding the ULP
may be useful to me...
in a private matter
Keep it.
I'm sorry I said all that stuff.
There was never a guy with a van.
I would never hurt your daughter.
I hope it was worth it.
Remember your NDA.
- Thanks.
- Remember your NDA.
Please remember you signed an NDA.
Remember your NDA.
Remember you signed an NDA.
Hey. Hey.
I know you're probably
still processing all that.
I just wanted to let you know I'm...
I'm gonna leave you alone.
I won't, like, follow you around
in regular life.
What?
I won't make more of this than it was.
I didn't think you were going to.
I have a problem with that. I...
I get weird.
Okay.
If that's what you think.
Bye, Annie.
Bye, Owen.
I'm sorry about...
everything.
I know it wasn't easy to bring me back.
It was the only choice.
The calculation failed, but I believe
it would have failed in any case.
I was the one who created an...
intolerable situation for Gertie.
The work you did with the GRTA
was remarkable...
Azumi.
Perhaps...
Gertie was the real project.
Room E, phase three?
- Hmm.
- Yeah.
Remarkable work they're doing up there.
I'm starting to think that your kiss,
not my mother's behavior,
was the catalyst for my...
temporary failure of my visual cortex.
During my hysterical blindness,
I had this...
vision that...
An internally generated vision...
It's called a fantasy, James.
Yes.
A fantasy.
You and I were at sea.
You were my first mate...
and nurturing life partner...
and we were on a journey.
To where?
The lost city of Atlantis.
Oh.
What is it?
- It's just I don't like boats.
- Oh.
Can I give you a lift somewhere?
You know how to drive?
My therapist told me
it might help.
Yes.
That sounds...
most excellent.
James, it's this one.
Of course.
There's no greater tragedy
than the destruction of a family.
You can be the one
to hold them all together.
- Daddy!
- Daddy's Home.
Share your joy with others
and make yourself feel whole again.
- I thought it was gonna be everyone.
- Just me.
You look nice.
How are you feeling?
- You don't have to be worried.
- I'm not worried.
You're worried I'm gonna ruin Jed's trial,
and I'm not, okay?
It's okay.
I think you're going to tell the truth
and help him.
It makes me proud.
Can't I be proud?
Yeah, you can. Sorry.
By the way, has...
anyone...
approached you and tried to get you
to change your story about Jed?
- What do you mean?
- Uh...
Have you encountered any strangers
trying to manipulate you?
Because I've heard
that sometimes these women
who make false accusations
against the wealthy
will sometimes hire people
to... to intimidate and confuse witnesses.
I think there's even a service.
No strangers, no.
Would you describe your brother
as a good person?
Yes.
Yes?
Have you ever seen
your brother engage in an act
of consensual or non-consensual urination?
- Absolutely not.
- And have you ever...
- We have a new settlement offer.
- What terms?
Generous.
How many times do I have to tell you guys?
We are not settling.
Why not?
Because it's bullshit. That's why.
Then I wouldn't have to lie under oath.
Look, this is a one-time thing.
My oldest son made a mistake.
Any settlement will ruin our family name.
And if this... woman,
if she can't find the generosity
to forgive Jed
for something that she agreed to,
then we as a family
will rip it out of her chest cavity.
That's a confusing metaphor.
That's how the Milgrim family
deal with our enemies.
Don't let this happen, Owen.
I'm a horrible person.
Adelaide's gonna leave me.
I don't know how this happened.
Jed...
These are real fucking tears, Owen.
You're either a part of this family
or you're not.
I buzzed him up at 7:05.
I know the time
because he's always five minutes late,
and I asked him to be there at seven.
And I know we were there for four hours
because that's how long
it takes me to beat him at Risk.
So, is it possible for Jed Milgrim
to have been at the office at 8:25?
Not unless someone could be two places
at the same time.
Objection, Your Honor.
There is no real documented time line.
- Overruled.
- No further questions, Your Honor.
Nobody can be two places at once,
but everyone has to be somewhere.
Do you agree, Mr. Milgrim?
I don't understand the question.
You have no data portals
in your micro apartment.
You live in a building with no doorman
and no security monitoring whatsoever.
- That's true.
- Why?
I prefer to be disconnected.
In a sense, you're invisible,
aren't you?
Sure.
Then let's see something visible.
At this point, Your Honor,
we'd like to introduce
the plaintiff's exhibit eight.
Video footage pulled
from the closed-circuit system
of the defendant's place of work.
Do you recognize this place, Mr. Milgrim?
That is the factory floor
of my father's company.
And this?
That's the stairwell
of my father's company.
What do you see happening here?
I see a man groping a woman.
This is the man
who used his power in the workplace
to force my client
into a heinous sexual act.
The defense's entire case
rests on you not believing
your very own eyes,
and instead believing Owen Milgrim.
Mr. Milgrim, were you diagnosed
with schizophrenia ten years ago?
Objection.
Irrelevant and prejudicial, Your Honor.
Overruled.
Answer the question Mr. Milgrim.
Are you schizophrenic,
Mr. Milgrim?
Yes.
Are you on any
anti-psychotic medications?
I'm supposed to be,
but I stopped taking them a while ago.
Do you ever get confused
about your brother, Jed?
As in you believe you're seeing him,
when, in fact, you are imagining
someone who just looks like him.
Not anymore.
And do you have trouble telling
the difference between what is real
and what's not?
- Sometimes I do, yes.
- Objection, Your Honor,
the witness is clearly having
a panic attack...
I would like to submit my testimony.
As I said before,
this entire case rests
on what Mr. Milgrim thinks of this image.
Does this man
look like your brother, Jed Milgrim?
It doesn't look like him.
See? I told you.
It is him.
What the fuck did he just say?
It's obviously him.
Motherfucker.
Just to clarify,
- your brother wasn't with you...
- I'm saying I lied, and he's guilty,
and he's a monster,
and I'm sorry for lying.
I'm not a liar.
He's guilty and he did it.
- No further questions.
- Your Honor, I move to redirect
and treat Mr. Milgrim
as a hostile witness.
It's too late, Counsel.
You've already examined him.
Motion denied.
No further questions, Your Honor.
You're dead. You're fucking dead.
I'm gonna kill you.
I'm gonna kill you my fucking self.
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
I need to tell you something.
I need to tell you
that it's not okay for me...
out here...
all by myself.
It was before, but it's not anymore.
Yes, you married a woman...
who was sick.
And she couldn't handle having a family,
and she left us.
And it broke your heart.
And then your daughter died.
And it was the wrong one.
It was the easier one...
who was good at life. Who made you laugh.
Who didn't cause problems,
who always called you.
Who didn't remind you of her mother.
And it's okay that you had to go in there,
but I don't accept it anymore.
I need you out here.
We are the only ones left.
I need you out here with me, Dad.
- I'm lonely.
- I take it your trip to Salt Lake...
opened things up.
What are you doing?
Annie, I don't think that,
what you said about the wrong one.
I don't... I don't think that.
Did you steal all my money?
I can pay you back.
When I saw how much you took,
I figured you weren't coming back.
I just figured, well...
there it is.
The third and final Irish exit.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
How was it?
I didn't go.
Not technically.
Your brain is not melted, at least.
It would have been painless, I heard.
According to the, uh...
insane computer.
She was going through a lot.
Well...
You seem good, Annie.
I don't feel good. How is she? How did...
- How'd she seem?
- Who?
Ellie.
Um...
None of that was real.
You get that.
I just... made up a version of her.
Maybe but, you know,
who really knows how this stuff works.
So, how'd she seem?
She seemed like herself.
Good.
Anything come to you
in the last three days?
I don't know. I think so.
But honestly, I feel confused.
I feel like maybe I did it wrong.
Owen listened to all of my stories.
But in the reflections, I kept giving him
all these reasons not to trust me,
but he just... kept trying to help me.
He acted like a friend.
I want to talk to you
about something
you've been avoiding since you got here.
Okay.
You talked about what happened
at the drug trial,
and you talked about
what you went through with your family,
but I still don't understand why you never
tried to talk to Annie again.
Because there were two options,
and neither could end well.
What are the two options?
Option A, she doesn't really exist.
I look up her name,
figure out where she lives,
and realize there's no one on Earth
with that name.
Next, I go
to Neberdine Pharmaceutical Bio Tech
and find out there's no such thing
as Neberdine Pharmaceutical Bio Tech.
What about option B?
Option B's even worse.
Owen, look.
I was so focused on my own shit.
I should have said I care about you,
and that after everything we've been
through, I can't not have you in my life.
Because it's really hard...
to actually just connect with somebody.
And... when you do...
you don't... You can't just run away.
Hey, Annie...
you don't have to explain it.
I know how special our connection is.
It means so much to me that you would
ask me to come with you to San...
to Salt Lake City.
Hmm.
Uh, Annie, I love you.
And I'm not gonna let my schizophrenia
get in the way
of these two big, beautiful beating hearts
because we're meant to be together.
Anna, I, uh...
- Um...
- What are you doing?
- Annie.
- No, no. You know what? No.
Will you marry me?
No.
- What?
- No? No.
- Just stop.
- Oh, I guess I misread the file.
Yeah, it's not like that at all,
and you're doing him wrong.
It needs to feel like pain,
but not an awful kind of pain.
It's like this low-level sadness
that has a lot of...
caring and sweetness underneath it.
Forget it.
That's a lot to remember, but, uh...
Are you firing me?
I can't lose another one, fuck.
This is...
This is real Owen.
Oh, they had me committed?
There's no way this is a coincidence.
This... This is a sign, Friend Proxy Owen.
Maybe the universe isn't total chaos.
That's comforting.
Let's do this.
Hey!
Oh, I wasn't going to get in any way.
Cue the music.
There she goes.
Okay, can't really drive stick.
Stuck in Bushwick.
God, I hate my fucking life.
Hello.
Would you sign in
and check your bag, please?
Oh, sure.
For you, sir.
- Hey, there.
- Hello. Just here to visit my niece.
My husband is already inside, so...
I'm late. I'm in trouble.
- Here you go. Thank you.
- All good?
- Okay, where should I go?
- Right here.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
What are you doing?
- What the fuck are you doing here, Owen?
- Moving benches.
- My family had me committed.
- I know that, idiot.
I mean, what are you doing in here?
This isn't even a state-run facility.
I'm crazy.
You're not fucking crazy, Owen.
Come on, you're just kind of crazy.
I made some threats to powerful people.
I sent anthrax to the governor.
Your brother did that.
I had a blip...
in college. I should be here. I'm sick.
Okay.
Maybe you're diagnosed,
maybe you need to be medicated,
but this...
This does not work for me, Owen.
I don't think it works for you either.
So you saw some things
that weren't there. So what?
People see aliens, people hear voices,
people see ghosts.
That's different.
My mind, it...
- It doesn't work right.
- No one's does.
I'm gonna go into that bathroom
right there...
and 30 seconds later,
you're gonna go into that bathroom.
You get me?
No.
What is the problem?
I'm afraid.
Of what?
Option B.
Annie, the same thing happens
every time I meet someone
or get close to someone.
I mess it up.
I'm gonna get frustrated...
one day, and yell at you out of nowhere,
over something insignificant
I'm fixated on.
And then you'll stop calling back.
And you'll change your number
and it'll break my heart.
It's just easier if you're not real.
But I am real.
You know me.
You're braver than this, Owen.
And I will never do that to you.
Never.
Thirty seconds.
Hey.
Come in here.
Come on.
Lock the door.
Our niece is out there.
We were visiting.
She's the one dancing by the wall.
It was a great visit,
but, you know, it's over now.
And you're Bruce.
I'm Linda.
Sorry these are weird. They're my dad's.
Owen, I saw this in a movie. It works.
Here.
Put 'em on.
Owen.
Annie, why are you here?
Because I'm your friend.
And that's what friends do.
Okay.
Hey.
Didn't you come in alone?
No, we were together.
You're seeing things.
Uh, I'm pretty sure you came in alone.
I'm pretty sure she came in alone.
Uh...
Let me see the sign in sheet.
- Is that the truck?
- Yes, yes, my dad gave it to me.
Just get in.
Let's go, come on. Go, go, go.
It's open! Get in!
That's Harpo. She's a rescue.
- Dammit.
- What's wrong?
This just happens
when I try to start cars.
Owen, will you go to Salt Lake City with me?
I don't technically have a driver's license.
Yes! You've gotta start the car, though.
Okay. Okay.
Go!
Okay, okay, okay. All right.
Annie, be careful!
Go, go!
Hey, hey!
Hey, hey, stop!
Annie, be careful!
I got it. We're good.
Shit, I missed the exit.
Hey! Stop!
Let go! We're good.
We're fine. We're fine. Bye!
Stop!
This is it.
It's a ridiculous theory.
More something my mother
would have cooked up.
- I'd like to hear it.
- Oh, you would?
- It's a long way to Newfoundland.
- Okay, yes. Well...
it begins like this.
Two billion years ago, an amoeba...
How far away is Salt Lake City?
It's far.
And I'm not entirely sure
this truck is gonna be able to get us
the whole way there,
but, you know, we'll get there one day.
Do we actually know each other?